こんにちは
アクティブインファレンスラボへようこそ
これは数学のストリームです
1.1 私たちの最初の数学のストリーム
そして今日は本当にラッキーです
少しの時間を持つことができて
シャナ・ドブソンと一緒にいて、私たちは
エマージェントタイムと
クロマティックタイプについて話します
このトピックについてもっと聞き、
皆さんの質問にもチェックインします
ライブチャットや
後のコメントにある質問
でもまず、私たちを簡単に紹介します
それからプレゼンテーションを聞き、
その後ディスカッションを行います
改めて、私はダニエルで、私の
共同主催者のサラと一緒にいます。サラ、こんにちはと言って
それから渡します
ええと、サラです。ウォークから電話しています
down forever berlin germany
and um i'm looking forward to
talking to shayna dobson
hey sarah thank you thank you for a nice
intro hello everyone my name is shanna
and uh i am uh i'll be a graduate
student in the fall but i've studied a
whole bunch of stuff
in the middle um i'm kind of a i guess a
polymath that
got a bunch of degrees at once and um
did a masters and i'm a i was hired
right away as a full-time lecturer kind
of everywhere
and um found a couple topics that i'm
pretty interested in
so let's see if uh if this can be
exciting for someone
shayna dobson sorry
okay daniel can you see this okay yep
all right am i ready to go okay good
um great all right so i want to talk
about
um emergent time and chromatic types and
you know maybe um i mean it's up to
y'all if you want to ask me questions as
i go or maybe hold them because i'm
trying to
constellate uh what's going on here
you're gonna see there's some heavy
topics involved
but i try to make them um as beautiful
and palatable as i can
so uh let's just get right to it what
are these and what am i talking about
so i have a few questions um kind of
driving this independent of the
mathematics i'm trying to make this not
super math focused i was trying to make
this kind of
すべての人により適用可能であるため、
私が行う数学は非常にニッチです。
それを避けて、
非包括的にならないようにしようとしていました。
だから大きな問いは哲学の
私を駆り立てている問いは何かというと、
時間とは何か、うーん、何か時間でないものはあるのか、
時間
時間は常に単に
ガイガーカウンターのようにモデル化されるか、
この種の受け入れられた背景として、
現象であり、私はそれにあまり同意しません。
私たちはそれにあまり焦点を当てていないと感じています。
人々はこう考えます、
それはどこにあるのか、
あなたは知っています、私は時々話をする時、
私の最初の質問は、
昨日はどこにあるのか、もちろん、
人々は「何を言っているの？」と思います。
ズームアウトして光を見てみることができるのに、
光円錐データやそのようなもの
しかし、現象学的には本当に
興味深い、どこにあるのか
そして、あなたは知っている、ええと、いつもここにあるのか
そして、私はラファエルと話していたのを覚えている
ブズーと
彼はあなたについての素晴らしい論文を持っている
知っている、つまり、いつもここにあるのか
そして
もしかしたら、それはそうではない、もしかしたらそれは一種の
ただ、もしかしたら
あなたはそれがある時点で来たことを知っている
したがって、私はそれが一種の
出現的で、私はいつもそうではなかった
ここにいて
おそらく適切な言葉ではない
あなたは私が言語を愛しているのを見ることになる
だから、再び私は超多才で、私は
私の数学論文の多くは超数学的で
哲学
and so i think there's a lot of
problematic terms
that we need to actually go into and so
i actually say where's non-archimedean
time
you know so um not an archimedean the
you know the
uh to be archimedean is to believe in
infinite decimals that you can always
have a number bigger or lower and
in quantum mechanics you really have a
cut off right so if quantum mechanics is
modeling
you know cut-offs as um you know spatial
cut-outs as
non-archimedean why is time not also
non-archimedean so i'm very interested
in that
what would that actually look like let
me go heavy into that so
あの、サラ、私はイリヤを持っていたんだ
それはデリダだ
フランスの大陸哲学において
常に「そこにある」ということを言っている
数学では常に「存在する」というところに行く
あなたは「存在する」ものがあることを知っている
xがあって、何でもそうだから、それは非常に
強力な存在量化子だ
そうだね
でも、そして量化子だけど、私は、あなたが知っているように
存在の条件は何か
これはクリス・フィールズと私が
取り組んでいることで、あなたはそれが何かを知っている
代謝条件だけではなく、私は
これすべてを意味する
あなたは知っているので、ビッグバンは
本当の問題だ
そして、あの、それに入るともちろん
あなたはこれらの野生の理論を持っている
あなたは知っている、まあ、あなたはそれがどういうものか知っている
ホワイト、あなたはホワイトホールのようなものを知っていますか
何か他のものを通り抜けて、すべてが
この種のもの
でも、私は本当に興味があるのは、
持つための条件は何かということです
存在
そうですね、ええと、何が
離散化を持つための条件ですか
時間の
それは一体何を意味するのか、では何が
エントロピーと時間の離散化なのか、
私たちは非常に曖昧な概念の
エントロピーを持っていて、私はマックス
テグマークに同意します、客観的な
エントロピーの概念はないと
あなたは、ああ、
ここにエネルギーの局所的な流入があるけれど、
あなたは知っていますが、周囲の環境は
エネルギーを失ったので、そこには
キャリブレーションがあるようです、あなたは知っています
だから私の全体のポイントは、ええと、カテゴリ化することです
ストップメカニズムは、クリスが
彼の最後の講演で話したように
ええと、生物学的に言えば、
いつ止めるか
ええと、細胞が分裂するように
ストップメカニズム
生物レベルでは非常に非常に非常に
複雑だと思います
それで、私はどうやってそれを
カテゴリ化するのか気になっています。つまり、
カテゴリ理論を使って
ええと、私の全体の雰囲気は、実際に
数学をアップグレードしようとすることです
それが使われています
これらのいくつかのことをモデル化するために再び
私の頭はかなり抽象的です
だから私は物事を抽象的に見ますが、私は思います
それは贈り物です。なぜなら、それが私に
つながりを見ることを許しているからです
in a non-linear way so my brain is
definitely non-linear and i try to use
that in linear
phenomena so i say you know how can we
say you know there exists a time
asymmetry but it uses this
like phrase well when there is no
objective notion of entropy
i think it's really really tricky
there's also no proven structural
causality
all right and sarah you had this you
know the light cone it's a little vague
right there's some problems uh with gr
there's some problems with the
formulation of light cone and things
like that
um light cones wouldn't withstand
quantum mechanics and stuff like this so
um i
あなたが知っていると固く信じています、ちょうど
バートランド・ラッセルのように、そこにはない
構造的因果関係があり、それはあなたを導きます
これらの素晴らしいことに、例えば
ラスト・サーズデー主義、そしてあなたは世界が
5分前に作られたことを知っています
そして、言うことに論理的な
不可能性は本当にありません
だから、私は構造的な
因果関係を見たことがありません
そして再び、クリス・フィールズと私は同意します
これに関して、だからこそ私たちは書いています
このクールなものを
第8に、なぜ私たちは実際に
記憶を体験するのか、これは実際にうーん
なぜこれが非常にうーん
再び当たり前にされているのか、だから私は
本当に興味があります
なぜそれがそうなのか、もちろん人々は言います
あなたは記憶を持っているのは、あなたを防ぐためです
崖から再び落ちることを知っている
連想と基本的なパブロフ的なもののように
あの、サバイバルのことで、それは違うんだ
私が話しているのはそういうことじゃないよね
実際には再び、どうやってのことを話している
なぜあなたは経験するのか
彼らは私のような誰か、まるで完全な
予知能力者のように、私はすべてを覚えている
そして時々、私は知っている、幽霊に悩まされることがある
思考のような、ただ浮かんでくる記憶に
入ってきて、私はたくさんのことを知っている
そういう人々がいるかもしれない、あなたはただ
テストを受けているのかもしれない
そしてこれらの恐ろしい記憶がただ飛び込んでくる
あなたの頭の中に、あるいは本当に良いかもしれない
記憶だよね
でもその経験は非常に
奇妙で、誰も思考が何かを知らない
そう、サラを覚えている、あなたが尋ねたと思う
サーとクリスのトークで
あなたは何が思考であるかを知っていますか、そして私は
私は何についても聞いたことがありません
あれは人々です、ああ量子揺らぎ
そしてこんなことですね、はい、でも
他に何かが起こっています、なぜなら
例えば、あなたが知っているように
私が今言ったスピーチは、私は読みました
番号八
約2分前に、そしてああ、だからその
スピーチは消えますよね、それは死にますが
何かが残ります
だからああ、それは何ですか、それはまるで
ホログラムがあります
あなたが言うすべてのコピーがそれで、
実際には脳に保存されています
そしてあなたは何らかのリコールを行っています
それを使ってですが、私はストレージを理解していません
すべてが離散的であるならば
だからこそ、これは非常に複雑で
非常に美しいので、私は言います
彼らはどんな感じですか、何が
思考の基本単位です、あなたは知っています
アラン・ワッツが言おうとしていること、ああ、それは
存在のようなもので、私は本当に確信が持てません
バイオの人たちが何を言うのか
それは何ですか、あなたは知っています、ええと、それは思考ではない
思考
あなたは知っています、私にとって、あなたは見ることになるでしょう
私がこのプロ有限を引き合いに出すことを
条件、プロ有限集合
は、ええと、コンパクトで完全に切断された
空間です、それはそうです
それはカンター集合のようです、だから私は思うのです
起こっていることは、時間がまるで
カンター集合のようです
そして、何らかの方法であなたは
カンター集合を思い出しています
思考とは何ですか、それはアイデアではありません、ええと
私たちがどのようにお互いに話しているのか全く分かりません
だから、私たちは実際に進む必要があると思います
over what that is these are just the
questions having begun the talk right
so questions two right what is causality
like what is it again if i don't believe
in structure you know oh a came before
b that's very reference frame dependent
and reference frames
are flimsy right and so i say well
causality for him
and then i say well what is a
measurement that's very tricky right of
course the quantum problem
and um just measurement in general yeah
and i say well what is a reference frame
that's even worse
um you know according to me my world
according to me
and like who is me and so that's going
to be tricky
so chris and i you know both agree like
what is this personal identity
over time and you've got big branches of
philosophy like pedurantism and
endurances i'm trying to just
trying to figure out what that is right
uh
who is this right uh is
is me today the same as me yesterday
well clearly not
because the cells are doing a whole
bunch of things right we don't have any
of the same cells that we used to have i
mean maybe some neuronal things
but um you know you have a boundary and
so what's happened so i you know i don't
understand what over time means i don't
know how anyone can be over anything
so then you know um sarah i said well
isn't you know uh shouldn't you talk
about space time and i'm like that's
ただの多様体で、それは数学における最も基本的な構造の一つのようなものです。
私たちはより洗練された数学を持っています。
だから、私はあまり、ええと、
その多様体の考え方には共感しません。
本当に、
それを輝かせて、実際に何が起こっているのかを見ることができます。
実際に何が起こっているのか。
あなたが実際にそれを統一する必要があるかどうかはわかりません。
そのように、ええと、
単に時間を空間化することができます。
時間をそのままにしておくのではなく、
だから、私はこう思います。もしあなたがしたいのなら、
単に、ええと、多様体と
微分幾何学を使うこともできます。
数論、
では、数論的な
時間はどのように見えるでしょうか、そして数論的な
空間はどのように見えるでしょうか。
だから、あなたは単に私全体を持つ必要はありません。
ポイントは
物理学は物理学の枠組みのようなものです
は、現在の数学に基づいています
現在の時点で
だから、多くの量子力学は
線形代数と演算子理論のようなものですが
あなたもまた
それを上げて代数的にすることができます
数論にして新しい
物理学を得るので、私と一緒に
新しい数学を与えれば新しい物理学が得られます
だから数学をアップグレードしてください
あなたは、だから、数とは何ですか
理論的なブラックホールは、私にはずっと
クールに聞こえます
あなたは、知っている、物理学の枠組みの
ブラックホール、古いモデルには多くの
問題があります
私を見えますか、はい、わかりました
クール
all right so let's go through this
outline and again i'll just keep the
talk
um at like an hour and then um
all right so here we go so those are my
like big questions kind of funneling
everything
um so i'll talk about discrete time i'm
going to really firmly say that there is
no synchronous reference that everything
that's happening now already happened
you do have like a lot of time in the
brain
to process so there is nobody's
experiencing anything as it is
and things like that i'm also going to
say that there really is no self
reflexivity because i
i don't know if that there's a self and
so
chris and i are trying to actually
formulate all this together right so i
really don't think there is a productism
or an endurantism with those two
philosophies that are trying to say
you know that you exist as a
four-dimensional being and you kind of
exist
through time and i think there's some
problems with that
so problems within produrantism or
endurance is like oh i get cut and i
have a reaction later
those those pieces of you were supposed
to be independent but they're not
we're in touch with our pain but they
would say that it's like not
so it's it's a little tricky um i think
there is no personal identity over time
i have no idea how this is happening
リセットが起こっているようです
毎回毎回、ええ、何でもあなたが
プランク時間と言いたくないかもしれませんが、もし
時間を超えた個人的なアイデンティティがないなら
確かに、あなたは知っているので、私は思います
ええ、記憶は何であれ、持っています
単一のサポート
サポートは、ええ、ええ、
関数が存在する場所
は
ゼロではないので、もし単一の
サポートしか持っていないなら、それはあなたがゼロではないことを意味します
単一の集合上で
だから実際に、ええ、私は試みています
これに使われる数学をすべて
アップグレードすることを
フラクタルやカントール集合のようなものに
それに色彩型を紹介します
色彩型は私が取り組んでいるこの新しい
スピンになるでしょう、ええ
それは、いわゆるものと平行しているようなものです
ホモトピー型
に基づく新しいホログラフィック原理
私が本当に好きなこれらのダイヤモンド
そして、出現する時間、さて、なぜかというと
どのように、そしてどの程度私が尋ねられたか
なんとなく埋めるために、私はなぜかと言った
この日、首尾一貫したものは存在しません
出現する時間の形式主義もなく
時間の離散化
連続体が存在しないと想像してみてください
それは大きな、ええ、それは大きな声明です
実際に存在するものは、
離散化の間に何が出現するのか
私たちの複雑性クラスを再びどうすることができるのか
チューリングの観点からの複雑性クラス
度合い、それが私が言及していることです
だから、サラ、同値類ではなく
チューリング度の同等のようなもの
あなたはまだこれを持っている、つまり存在するのです
そしてそれが
時間の物理学はの同等物です
意味のある大統領ですが、それは欠けています
すべてのカズーのストリームは、業界が
最も柔らかい木のように、私たちは
物理学の詭弁がたくさんあり、
数学的な詭弁があり、私はどうすることができるのかと思っています
実際に
私たちが実際にどうやってうまくやれるかを考えようとしています
持つ
この離散化による存在を
時間
どんな陰謀とも独立して、あなたは
私たちがどれだけうまくやるかを知っているので
願わくば素晴らしい紹介を持つことができる
数学的にすべての離散化は
それは委員長と一緒です、わかりました
だから、私はたくさんの
数学に興味があります、あなたは構築することができます
空間
based on algebraic spaces so
i'm going to try to go really lightly
through this because this is pretty
heavy
but um so you can quotient out a scheme
which is like a higher dimensional
notion of an algebraic variety
by a pro-ital equivalence relation pro
tells us
a certain topology an equivalence
relation is going to be a gluing
so you get this diamond which is a sheaf
on a category
in a category called perfectoid spaces
so this diamond has these quote
impurities which are these geometric
points i refer to
so this is a notion from peter schulza
and i
really like the the diamond idea and um
それで、あなたがこれを持っていると何が起こるかというと、ええ
これは、モルフィズムである幾何学的点です
スキームの
そして、ほぼ、ええ、それはそれで
このようなもので、そこには
このオブジェクトに数学的な不純物があります
そして、
通常のダイヤモンドを持っていると、ええ、あなたは
それに異なる色があることを知っています
それは不純物の反射です
しかし、実際にはその
不純物自体は見えません
あなたはただの反射を見ているだけです
不純物の反射を見ているだけで、あなたは決して
実際にあなたが得ているものを
実際にはシフトされた
反射のバージョンを得ているだけです、それが私が
ここで起こっていると思うことです
そうですね、あなたはあなたの、ええ、あなたの
インターフェースを持っています
and no one's ever actually experiencing
the thing just a profiling many copies
so
you could you can pull this morphism of
a scheme back which is a topological
move
and you can get this what's called a
profanity many copies of spa
see this is the attic spectrum of an
algebraically closed
curve so you can make these products spa
c cross
s underline for s underline being a pro
finite set which i described earlier
so you can get these awesome products
and um this is
this is the new like model that i use to
uh write um this cool paper with my
awesome colleague robert pretner
about a new model of consciousness where
it's like okay
this is what's going on you know you
have profiling many copies of this of
a perception it's you're not really
perceiving
so um but that that's pretty deep that's
the some of the hardest math on the
planet it's like looking at sheaves
on um a category so discretized time
right so something i came up with just a
bit ago was like there you know there
really is no
you can't really say a equals b whatever
you want to say that
really what you're saying is a equals b
up to some condition
x where x is what is called a homotopy
type
so type theory is like uh pretty rampant
in the
えっと、たくさんの素晴らしいモデルがあるんだよね
それで、ホモトピックタイプはこうなるんだ
それは同値だよ
それは基づいている同値だよ
ホモトピーは変形のことだよ
二つの空間の間で、だからaは
基準xが考慮されるならbに等しいと言える
だから本当に気をつけなきゃいけないんだ
等しいという表現には
そうだね、だから本当に私たちは
特定のメトリックに関してのみ
相互主観的合意があると思う
何に対しても平等はないと思う
ただエージェントの集まりが合意しているだけだよ
これらのメトリックについてね、えっと
素晴らしいドン・ホフマンはそれに関してたくさんの
研究をしているし、えっと
彼の研究グループで少し働いていたんだ
だから、私はそれが
メンテーション、これらの生物学的プロセスだと思う
just give a
um a talk on like mentation and
a certain homotopy type um that it
actually works in discrete time so how
are you actually going to do that
how can you actually model memory and
biological functions
over a discretized time that looks like
a bunch of dots so that looks like
memory of a singular support and you're
going to have to
really figure out how you could get
words and things like that
so what i'm going to do is like
introduce those chromatic types
so again there's no personal identity
over time i think you only have
chromatic towers of localization i'll go
over that
but in your singular support you're
ローカリゼーションと呼ばれることを行っている
ローカリゼーションは追加する方法の一つです
逆元、例えば
整数ですね
逆元を追加したい場合は
整数に対して何かのようなものを得る必要があります
有理数
逆元を追加することは空間をより
充実させる方法です
私はそう言います、そしてまた取ることができます
カテゴリ
射を持つもので、射を作ることができます
射の同型、つまり
それらは可逆であることを意味します
ローカリゼーションは非常に強力ですので
再度言いますが、個人的な
アイデンティティはありません、ええと、唯一のものは
個人的なアイデンティティです
時間に関しても、私はわからないと思いますが
時間は条件の一つかもしれません
あなたが存在するために
あなたは本質的に各
特異点の支持を局所化しています
そして、私は書いたと思います、そう、私は
これについての小さな論文を書きました、それは
ジャーナルに出るはずです
認知科学の、だから期待しています
そこにあるので、これは何ですか
ホモトピー型は位相空間です
弱いものまで考慮される
ホモトピー同値、ええと、ああ、何ですか
それは位相空間であり、考慮されます
ええと、あなたが知っているように
ああ、あなたが知っているように、実際にどのように
空間内のさまざまなオブジェクトを等しくすることができるか
無限群体と呼ばれるもの、ええと
あなたは無限群体を得ることができます
すべての
射は実際に
すべてのマップは実際に可逆です
弱ホモトピー同値を呼びます
位相空間間の写像であり
誘導します
すべてのホモトピック群における同型写像
ホモトロピック群はエンコードされています
うーん、ホモトピーの振る舞いとそう
それが私があなたに推薦した本にあると言います
あなたに推薦しました
群については、私たちは群に慣れています
あなたは対称性がどこにあるかを知っています
オブジェクトを自分自身に関連付ける
しかし、群があると対称性があります
複数のオブジェクト間で作用するように
これのように見ることができます
このビジュアルでは、a b c d これらがあります
複数のオブジェクトがあり、写像があります
どこにでも行っています
うーん、群体はすべての
射が同型写像であるカテゴリです
無限群体を持っている場合
無限の意味は無限の
モルフィズムは無限の同型なので
色彩型の大きなアイデアは
実際に色彩タワーを置くことです
私たちが皆知っている時間論理の上に
時間論理と
私が言っていることがわかるでしょう
このタワーを見て、実際に
作成することができると思います
ホモトピーの代わりに色彩型を
型
私たちはこれらの
色彩空間を作成することに興味があります
それぞれの独自の概念を持つ
局所化
そして新しい時間の概念を得ることができます
幾何学的ホモトピックを局所化するので
再び、局所化は方法であると言いました
加えることの
カテゴリー理論における逆元を意味します
あなたは地図を作りたいのです
同型を考えると、あるカテゴリが与えられたとき
c は射のクラス w にあり、私たちは
局所化を求めます
c w の逆を使うと、反射的なものを得ることができます
局所化
あなたがすることは、局所化することで、つまり
逆を加えることで、空間を完成させます
もしそれがコーシー空間で、あなたが
列を収束させたい場合はどうなりますか
そして逆限を取ります
それは接続することで、私はたくさんの接続を行うのを見ます
接続をたくさん行います
カテゴリについてですが、カテゴリは
オブジェクトと射の集合であり、
あなたには結合律の条件があり、
単位矢印があります
したがって、ホモトピーは再びマップであり、オブジェクトを同値にする方法です
オブジェクトを同値にする方法はいろいろあります
そして、あなたにはさまざまな方法があります
それができるので、私は興味があります
トポロジカルと呼ばれる何か
ローカリゼーション、これは別の
トピックのローカリゼーションのタイプですので、私たちは
トポロジカルローカリゼーションは左正確です
ローカリゼーション、そして再び私は行こうとしています
これらのいくつかに非常に穏やかに
定義
無限の左正確ローカリゼーション
1カテゴリー、つまりそれは
無限のモルフィズムのカテゴリーです、ええと、
反射的と呼ばれるものに移行する
サブ無限1カテゴリーの
モルフィズムのコレクションで、
単射です
詳細については、
もちろん、それらは重要ですが、ええと、
全体のポイントは、あなたが持っていることです
反射的な
サブカテゴリー、それは反射的なものですか
サブカテゴリは完全なサブカテゴリです
オブジェクトdとその
射は反射を持っています
カテゴリの中で、それはとてもクールです
オブジェクトと射は
dのすべてのオブジェクトは自分の
反射を特定の
射tで見ます
dからtdへのオブジェクトの反射
cは実際に
同型を備えています
それは素晴らしいことです、包含は
すべての限界を作り、すべてのクールな限界を持っています
それは除外しますので
限界と
コ限界を持つということは、あなたのカテゴリが
ある種の
非常に非常にうまく振る舞うことを意味します、これは
とても素晴らしいです
反射的サブカテゴリでは
非常に適切なようです
それをダイヤモンドの作業と組み合わせるために
私がやろうとしているのは
ええ、ダイヤモンドは扱っています
これらの精巧に作られたコピー
反映
そして反射のサブカテゴリーはご存知の通り
含まれています
ええ、実際の物体の反映を
非常に特別なものです
ええ、サブカテゴリーです
ですから、全体のアイデアは大丈夫です
ですから、もしかしたら毎瞬あなたは
実際に位相的に
ローカライズしていて、それは実際に意味します
あなたは実際に自分自身を見ているだけです
常に反映を見ているということです
そうですね、たくさんの格言があります
あなたが見るものはあなた自身です
絶対にそうです、ええ、私はまだあなたを知っています
so
i'm using all of that beautiful
mathematics to actually justify a
statement
that you know would only like without
the mathematics the statement would just
be like
a sentence and i can actually try to
justify it structurally
so i think you're actually localizing
time as these kinds of equivalences
so there really is no well-defined
notion of metric you really just have
uh you know why why are we working in
topological spaces because the metrics
are very subjective
and so you work topologically or you
don't really have a notion of metric but
you have a closeness condition
so everyone works topologically and i'm
時間の概念をカテゴライズしようとしている
そして空間はそれを投げ込むことを意味する
カテゴリー理論
そのモルフィズムとそれをどのように
ローカライズするかについて話しましょう
そしてモルフィズムをどのように反転させるか
尋ねる必要があります
ああ、あなたはトポロジカル空間を知っているので
空間にトポロジーがあります
だからここで、ダイヤモンドのように
私はそれを置く、あなたは知っている、うーん
あなたは知っている、ピーターはあなたの上にシースを置く
カテゴリーの中で、はい
では、カテゴリーにおける開集合とは何ですか
実際にはそれは簡単ではない
そうですね、うーん、だから私は言います
トポロジカルの構成
ローカリゼーションはその構成において適切にメタのように見える
何の反映の構成において
すでに無限に多くのコピーがあるもの
vスタックという言葉を言うと、それはより高い
ダイヤモンドの概念
それについては後で少し詳しく説明します
それで、第二のメタ
質問は、実際にどのようにして
無限の1のようなトポロジーを
カテゴリに置くかということです
それは難しいですよね、実際に
開集合が何であるかを理解しなければなりません
カテゴリの中で、基本的に
点集合トポロジーと、何でもそうですが
ハッチャーが説明することになります
あなたはトポロジカル空間と
トポロジーについて知っていますが、実際に
カテゴリにそれを得るのは簡単ではありません
無限の1の上に無限の1サイトと呼ばれるものがあります
無限の1カテゴリの上に
それは無限の1のデータエンコーディングです
無限の1シーブのカテゴリの
シーブはプレシーブを参照します
ある特定のプレシーブのカテゴリの内部
えっと、そうですね
えっと、これはクリスの言った通りです
話すと、これは
ローカルデータを監視する方法のようなものです
空間の周りで
シートは特定の空間に接続されています
それで、私たちは呼びます
えっと、サイトのカテゴリ上のトポロジーを
この色彩塔は何ですか
色彩塔はこのように見えます
えっと、実際には
たくさんの研究があります
色彩ホモトピー理論に関して、ただ
これを差し込むだけです
でも、それは何ですか？それは
これらの色彩を使って空間を特定する方法です
塔の
これが与えられたln、これはブーストフィールドです
マラバKと呼ばれるものの局所化
理論なので、これらの k 理論は
ベクトルの同型類を見る方法です
バンドル
そこにウェッジ和があります、ええと、そして
ええと、この局所化の接続ですね
局所化は逆元を追加することです
ええと、それを考慮して、私たちはそれを呼びます
色彩塔のホモトピー限界
これらのものの塔があります
スペクトルと呼ばれるもので、これは
コホモロジー理論のように振る舞い、
コホモロジー理論は
空間の穴を探求し、
データのような素敵な不変量について
空間を分類したいので、これらの
空間があります
そして、これらの塔は
スペクトルのレベルに基づいています
これはモー、これは私がええと、私が言うときのことです
p のことを
localization of a spectrum that's uh
it's pretty detailed but
uh we're saying like it's localized with
respect to a certain p
and so without without like
super going into the details of that you
have uh
towers of equivalences and so based on
your layer
based on where you are on the chromatic
tower
is what you're going is how you're going
to be navigating
so that's memory space to me recall
memory space it's all the same
navigating your touring degree
is is in a sense a chromatic tower like
this so to create a chromatic type
i'm going to make uh equivalences based
on the layers of this tower
so for instance you know if you're on
the top layer making a
an equivalence between the top layer
and uh you know um so replacing
home never replacing but upgrading the
homotopy type
with chromatic type okay
so we say for memories and computability
i said uh again at that mentation talk
that i just gave not too long ago at the
biological conference
what else besides computing might be
involved in biological mentality right
i'm just going a little um
phenomenological so we can pull this
together but you know it's a it's a
homotopic type that could be a chromatic
type
it proceeds by weak equivalences it far
exceeds there's a lot of like expander
それをモデル化するグラフとグラフ理論
私はそれが不十分だと思います
そして、あなたがこれらに入ることができると思います
タワーに行ってもう少し得る
何が起こっているのか、だから私は記憶とも言います
ほとんど謝罪のように進行するそれは
非常に厳格な言葉です
故障、ほとんどであることの意味
しかし
私たちは記憶が一つの
サポートを持っていると言えます、私が言ったようにカントールのように
集合
そしてそれは降下と呼ばれるものです
私の意見では、これは
接着
そう、記憶は想起であり、それは
すべてをまとめることです、そうすればあなたは
実際に
この特定の瞬間に位置づけることができます
それが何であれ
そしてそれはより降下のように振る舞います
条件は再び弱い同値性です
特定の中の写像のクラス
カテゴリ
計算可能性、そうですね、たくさんのものがあります
あの、すごいmsriの素晴らしい
msri会議、ええと
2020年のプログラムについて
決定可能性、定義可能性、そして
計算可能性
だから計算可能性は、問題を
効果的な方法で解決する能力です
あなたはこれらすべての計算を持っています、チューリング
計算可能
弱いオートマトン、強いハイパー
計算、私は言います、あなたは知っています
私はそれが実際に構築する能力だと思います
降下条件を、だから私は思います
私たちは取る必要があります
これらの非常に厳格な用語について、どのように
ナビゲートして
それらをカテゴライズして、私がどのように見えるかを理解する
追加する
では、なぜそれをアップグレードしないのか
そこに使われる数学をアップグレードする
ええと、能力について定義する
知識と概念を構造化する
形成の決定可能性
二項決定問題は決定可能であると言う
そこにはただ効果的な方法がある
正しい答えを導き出すことを知っている
そしてこれは非常に、ええと、これは非常に親切です
の、ええと
明らかにそうではない、これは私が
色彩の塔であなたに与えていたものではない
もっと多くの方法があると思う
回り道して
物事が実際に効果的であると言う
この種の弱い同値を使うなら
種類
だから記憶、他に何があるのか
情報アルゴリズムが関与しているのは
生物学的な
メンタリティ、まあたくさんあるよ
幾何学的論理の帯と完全性
特異な
サポート、そう、これを私は自分の中で呼んでいる
ロバートとの論文で、私たちは考え出した
ネストされた階層
意識の、そしてそれについては
約1秒で、私はこれを一体性と呼ぶ
一つの意識の構築能力
間の
他の一つの意識と、だから私たちは皆
意識を関連付けている、何であれそれは
幾何学的で関係的、私は思わない
それは計算的な
だからこのカテゴリー的なものを得ることができる、私は
方法を考え出そうとしている、ああ
あなたは、チューリングの概念を知っている
degrees let's get a categorical notion
of that
so um you know i say recall
your ability to recall is what's called
a localization sequence this is a
co-fiber sequence
where you have these maps and you have a
condition between functors
and what pops out is a fiber
and so you given so this is what i think
is happening when you actually recall
you look for a certain state
out pops a memory right so there's a
bunch of category theory going on
so what are the fundamental units of
life that's very tricky
right um there's a lot of um i think
there's a story about
like a beautiful monk that went up to a
hill to just um sort of self desiccate
and everyone thought he passed away but
maybe he had one heartbeat a year
so my question is like what what is that
what are the fundamental units
of life could it be that someone slips
under the radar
of what we would call metabolic life but
there's another set of brain waves
that are maybe mirror symmetries on the
other side so like you see i have this
chromatic tower with everything on the
right
side i want to build a what's on the
left side
so all of this i have chromatic towers
with right sides yeah so maybe this is
the condition of life and what if you
reflect it on the other side what does
that even mean
um so again i'm you know playing around
uh
trying to figure out levels of
consciousness so for instance clyde
wearing the famous case
um awesome pianist right super brilliant
pianist um
got an um i think an hpv and got an h
like uh got a retrograde amnesia and so
he's got a seven second memory and he
only has motor memory and no personal
memory
right so you can be like you know he'll
say i've never seen a doctor before in
my life and he's visited by doctors all
the time
so it's very interesting with someone
like that you have to ask the conditions
of what are clive waring's fundamental
units of life
and i literally think what you could you
何が起こっているのかをより簡単に分類できる
逆行性健忘症と言うよりも
逆行性健忘症
タワーの層の中にいくつかの層があるかもしれない
色彩の塔の中の層が、ええと
消えてしまった、それが起こっていることです。だから、もし
色彩の塔の層が切られたら
実際にあなたは、ええと、知っているので
これはすべてを解釈する幾何学的な方法のように
解釈することができます
さて、離散時間に移りましょう
離散時間
なぜ私たちは時間を連続的にモデル化するのか、例えば
なぜ
再び、私はそれが見落とされていると思いますし、ええと、私は
ただ考えています
私たちはそれに焦点を当てていないので、なぜ私たちは
時間をカウンターとしてモデル化するのか、または
何らかの
あなたが知っている背景依存モデルのための背景として
右、ええ、ここに描かれているのは
スペクトル系列と呼ばれるものです
そして、もし時間がこれらの系列のように見えるなら
点の中には空間に関する
たくさんの情報がエンコードされています
だから、時間をまるで
モジュライズされた空間のようにモデル化することができ、それが私が言ったことです
ええ、クリスが私たちに言ったとき、そうですね
点は単なる点ではありません
実際にはエンコードされています
他の情報を、しかしあなたはそれを見ることができます
点の間には隙間があります
だから、もし時間を不連続としてモデル化するなら
または、あなたが知っているように
または離散化された場合、実際に何が
隙間の間にあるのか、そうすると私たちは言います、はい
量子力学のモデル空間は
非アウフコメディアン場です
なぜ時間もまた非アウフコメディアンではないのか
なぜそうではないのか
それで、私はその質問で始めました。何が
現象学的に持つことを意味するのか
離散的な時間、t1とt2の間に何が存在するのか、
それは本当に豊かです。
実際にそこにあるものは、もしかしたらサスキンが
ピラミッドだと言うかもしれません。
出現、そう、彼は二つのブラックホールを持っています。
絡み合った彼は出現が
ブラックホールの絡み合いから来ると考えています。
だから、みんなそれを見ています。
そして、あなたは父権主義と
時間的部分を再び得ます。それはあなたがどこに
存在するかを教えてくれます。
時間を越えて、空間を越えて存在するように。
ええと、
私は、なぜ私たちが経験するのかを尋ねました。
記憶は時間と絡み合っているのか、
絡み合いはどこで終わるのか、それが私の
質問です。
記憶は実際にどのように存在するのか。
離散時間は難しい
それは難しいですね、だからもう一度あなたは
私のような誰かがいると思う、そこには
時間を超えた個人的なアイデンティティはないが、それでもあなたは
記憶を持っている
そうですね、なんとなく、ええと、とにかく、どうやって
実際に時間の終わりにおける記憶を定義しますか
私はただ一つのタイムラインがあるとは思わない
ここに
私はこの理論をまとめました、そこで私は
あなたが持っていると思います
時間のレベルはあなたが持っているのは
あなたがいるカテゴリーのレベルによって
そしてそれについて説明します
あなたがナビゲートできる時間のレベルは
あなたの複雑さに依存します
クラスと
実際にナビゲートできる空間のレベル
では、私たちは時間の終わりに記憶をどのように体験するでしょうか
nを持っていると想像してみてください
levels of time in a tower so uh with
roberts and our pluralist manus paper
and also the perfecto diamond paper
right we'd say you know awareness
is a it's i we can do it
representationally say it's a
representation of a pneuma non but we
also want to throw consciousness
into levels and layers
so right here you have a basic notion of
a one category where i have
objects and i have morphisms between
objects that's it
so one category is contains objects and
one
morphism so just a quick category theory
like um category is beautiful and i
cannot do it justice in two seconds but
i'm given just a little recap of what we
need
ここでは二つのものが見えます
カテゴリー二はカテゴリーを含みます
オブジェクト一つと、私たちが呼ぶものの間の射
二つの射、つまり二つの射または
射
射の間に、私はここに
f1からg2へのマップがあります、だからこの料金は
そして、私はf2からのガンマを持っています
g1へ
だから、これは私が考えていることを得ています
そうですね
基本的な複雑性クラスは、ただ
こんにちはダニエル、こんにちはサラ、私たちは
相互作用があります、それは
それで正しいですが、超予知者や誰でも
私のように完全な記憶を持つ人は
この相互作用の間にマップを置くことができます
この相互作用の中で、これが私が
話していることです
三つのカテゴリー、三つのカテゴリーはこのように見えます
このように、あなたは物体を持っています
物体間の射があります
あなたは一つの間の射を持っています
射
そして、あなたは三つの射を持っています、それは
二つの射の間の射です
これを見ることができます
f2がこの方向に進んでいます、つまりこれが何かというと
あなたのレベルに依存していると言っています
カテゴリーのレベル、あなたの意識のレベルが
あなたが
三つの意識を持つ生物であれば、あなたは
このように
ナビゲートすることができ、だからこそ私は
そう言ったのです
もしあなたが三つの意識を持つ生物であれば、あなたは
三つの時間に生きています
もしあなたが一つの意識を持つ生物であれば、あなたは
一つの時間に生きています、ええ
そして再び、私はただこれに進んだだけです
なぜなら、私のような人々は、
悩まされているか、
悲しい思い出に悩まされているか、祝福されているか、
素晴らしい思い出と時間に恵まれているか、
私にとっては、線形に進むようには思えなかった、
こういう感じで、まずこれがある、
主観的な経験があり、これがある、
表現の入れ子のカテゴリーが、
あなたは一つの意識を持っている、
あなたは二つの意識を持っているので、それは意味する、
カテゴリーのカテゴリーの、
表現の三つの意識、
カテゴリーのカテゴリーのカテゴリーの、
表現、
意識の中で、私たちのトップはカテゴリーの、
カテゴリーのカテゴリー、
だから、あなたは見ることができる、それが何を何を何をするのか、
このようなものは、まあ、
私があなたにこの素晴らしいプレゼンテーションをしていること、
歓迎されていること
in your environment and uh us also
you know uh being at the cambridge
apostles and having like
tea you know so not just being able to
imagine something like that but being
able to partition your brain
and split your consciousness and to
actually be able to do that
so i'm all i'm really excited about
splitting consciousness and trying to
physically be in multiple places because
i don't think
i don't think there's only one timeline
here but to split consciousness you'd
have to be able to do this in the brain
you know um which is cool so we come up
with so along with in time
and so again you can see that with the
mathematics you're able to do a lot of
stuff here
so within time i came up with this so
you know what i think according to end
time you'd have a pro finite language
like what is that well if you you know
any dairy dog piece or anything
like a in his of hermetology it's going
to show you that the the glossomatics or
the gloss seems you know your
fundamental units of language if you
open them up there's not a lot there
but actually the process of reading is a
trace it's a wild phenomena
because you're pulling together uh so
many pieces so we actually uh i came up
with this awesome language scheme that
was like well
you know uh in in the one space you just
have your normal i
we you know uh me my mine
but in n2 you'd have like a one eye a
二つの目、これは二つの中にいるならば
意識、もしあなたが二つの中にいるならば
カテゴリー
そうすると、実際には一つのようなものを持つことになるでしょう
目が一つ、目が二つ、私が二つ、私が一つ
あなたが三つのカテゴリーにいるならば
あなたは一つの目、二つの目、三つの目を持つことになるでしょう
目が一つ、私が二つ、私が
だから、ただ彼女、彼女だけではなく、
三つの彼女のようなものがあるでしょう
三つの彼女、そして私はそれがレベルだと思います
新しい言語の複雑さの
物理学のいくつかのことに触れると
そして、ええ、出現する時間に入っていくと
うーん、私はこのアイデアを思いつきました
完璧な辞書、再び完璧なもの
空間、またはピーター・シュルツの素晴らしい作品
そして私はそれが素晴らしいと思います
そして、ええ、私は量子物理学が
少し革命的である必要があると思います
ヒルベルト空間の置き換え
完美体空間の状態の置き換え
ベクトルは幾何学的な点で、私はただ
ここで講演をしました
UCLAのIPAMエントロピー会議で、あまり前ではなく
かなり良い反応を得たと思います
受け入れられました
テンソル積を置き換えて
ダイヤモンド積を非局所性と置き換え
プロフィネットと多くのspa cのコピー
重ね合わせをこれらで置き換え
プロイタルシーブとプロ有限集合
波動関数の崩壊は
非常に難しかったので、置き換えて
ティルティング操作と呼ばれるものに
特性ゼロから
特性pに移行します
これらの完美体モジュラー
曲線を置き換え
ホログラフィック原理をアップグレードして
六つのファンクター形式
これは成長と解体であり
今からお見せします
量子トポロジーのアップグレードを置き換えることができます
それをこの共通論で置き換えます
オペレーターを再び置き換えるのは素晴らしいです
しかし、単にものをアップグレードすることができますので
置き換えるとは言うべきではなく、アップグレードです
さあ、さあ、さあ、ええと、置き換えましょう
オペレーター代数を非テリアンで
ええと、バージョンとユニタリティを
特定の降下データを持っているので、これがあります
ええ、これはええと
ピーターのええええ六つのファンクター形式
どこで
六つのファンクター形式では、理論を作る方法です
本当に言うならば
ええ、それはええとそれは
置き換えるという概念です
ポアンカレのええと通常の点の正確な二重性
アベリアン主コホモロジーとそれの
ヴェルディエの双対性と呼ばれる何かがあるので
ここで双対性が進行しているので
だから私はそれが素晴らしいと思った
ホログラフィックと組み合わせるために
原則はホログラフィックであるため
原則は
フアン・マルドシナの広告によって本当に強化されている
CFT
あなたが知っている、ええと、提案された双対性の間で
ゲージ重力双対性のように、あなたは
このええと
私が取り組んでいるダイヤモンドのFMFK理論のことがある
そしてこれらの
ええと、6つの操作があり、これらとともに
6つの操作は、単に画像の
ファンクター間の
シーブと、ええと、あなたはこの概念を得る
これが私が考えていることです
だから、ええと、量子重力では、あなたは持っています
ホログラフィック原理とそれはまだ
非常に緩やかに
ええと定義されていて、それはそれはそれは与えられたものです
そしてそれはただの否定的な
条件はそれが何でないかによって定義される
だから私はホログラフィック原理を考えています
ええと持つ代わりに
広告はご存知の通り反シッター空間の中に
中央と共形場理論の中に
バルクの中で実際に持つことができる
中央に六つのファンクター形式があり
無限に多くのコピーのように
ダイヤモンドのええと
共形場定理のように見える
これが私が今取り組んでいることです
だから出現する時間ええとこれらのVスタック
これらは
高次元のダイヤモンドであり、だから
確かにホログラフィックです
ええと、彼らはすでにエンコードされているという意味で
データの非常に多くのコピーがあるそれは
すでに二つの面で複数です
ええと、vスタックは二重シーフです、だからこれは
あなたが知っているシースのようなもので、
あなたを寒さから守ります
ローカルデータをエンコードします、だからこれは今、それは
一つの
それは一つ上のカテゴリで、ええと値を取ります
カテゴリの中で、むしろ
集合ではないので、あなたは知っている、あなたは
vスタックに移行する必要があります、もしあなたがええと
このプロファイリング言語を行いたいなら
ええと、ここにクリスとの推測があります、そして
私は、私たちは一般化しようとしています
分離可能と絡み合ったの違いを
これは簡単ではありません
ええと、
再び思い出してください、幾何学的な
ダイヤモンドアモルフィズムの中の
スキームの点には、何かが呼ばれています
ベアワイズシリコン
そしてインフォモーフィズム、これは随伴です
対
えっと、だから大丈夫、あなたは随伴を持っています
対、これはちょっと似ています
逆のような逆関数ですが
彼らは、えっと
ファンクターで、私たちはこのアイデアを拡張します
二つの随伴対
えっと、これは f 上付き星、えっと rf
えっと、下付き星は導出カテゴリのためのものです
そして次に f 下付きシュリークと f 上付き
シュリーク、シュリークは
句読点のスラングのようなものです、だから
それらは再び指しているのは
ピーターの演算子、だからそれが壮大な
対応関係、右側はこれになります
えっと、この導出カテゴリは構成されていて
正確にはアテルの
これらの特定のモジュールのシーブです
small diamond
okay so let's get to emergent time so
how what am i i'm gonna use all this how
do i actually
pull this together so if you consider
the simplest case we say an event
what is an event it's a i'm going to
call it a topological localization of
any particular reference frame
right event is normally like i don't
know simultaneity or says something like
that
try not to use the word simultaneity so
we'll say a topological localization of
somebody's reference frame
let's consider that to be a point in the
diamond topological space on that point
is a certain site i told you right
that's how you're going to get a
topology
we're going to call this site the pro
hotel site the category of pro finite
sets
s so this is from
more of peter's work on condensed
mathematics so global time emerges as a
set of continuous maps from all pro
finite sets
s to t so again you have these chopped
up notions of time and you can get
global time to emerge as the
set of continuous maps from again the
all the pro finite cantor sets
back to t back to the topological space
so global time could be considered as a
sheaf of sets on this pro hotel site
and that's called a condensed set based
on his work with uh um
clausen so emergent time results in
passing to the larger category of she's
これの簡潔なバージョンを考慮するために
これは私が望まないf理論の構築です
あまり多くを説明するのは避けたいです、少し深いです
したがって、もう一つの推測的な方法で得るために
実際に出現する時間を
ダイヤモンドを使用し、それらの同値関係を取ることができます
実際に得るために、ええと
vスタックを、だから再び私があなたに見せたとき
ダイヤモンドの定義をあなたは
あなたの同値関係を取りました
プロテル同値関係
さて、アップグレードしましょう、そしてあなたは取ることができます
実際に同値関係を
ダイヤモンドからvのモジュライズ空間を得るために
スタック
それはかなり大きいので、新しい作業があります
実際にどうするかについて行われています、あなたは
知っています
新しい代数についてはどうですか、これはピーター
とダスティンの新しい作業です、どうやってやるのですか
代数と
環と加群はトポロジーを持つ
このことは素晴らしいと思う
そしてここが私のいる場所で、まるで「やあ」と言っているようだ
私たちは何かをしなければならない
数学を活性化させる必要があり、アップグレードが必要だ
物理のいくつかのことに移行する必要があり、私は思う
うーん、私たちは皆そこから学べるので、もしあなたが
関数解析を
可換代数の一分野に変えることができれば
それは非常に素晴らしい、
代数幾何のバージョンを構築することができる
収束する冪級数の環を基本的な
ビルディングブロックとして、私の質問は
実際に分析を行う方法は
非アルキメデス幾何学で、そう、それは
実際には少し難しい
そして数学者にとっては興奮することだ、そうだよね
だから、何らかの
完全性条件を加群に置きたい
あなたはそれらが模倣するものを知っています
ベクトル空間のようですが
ええと、スカラーはフィールドではなく、彼らは
リングから来ることができます
リングの係数とそのように
自由な対象が振る舞うように
ある種の冪級数のように代わりに
はい、代数的なものを構築できます
幾何学、アベリアンの
アベリアン群のカテゴリーから始めることができます。あなたは
テンソル積を持っていて、それは単に
整理する方法です
そして、このようなカテゴリーの中でリングを考慮することができます
あなたは関連付けることができます
spec rを、私が示したのと同じspa rに
ダイヤモンドの中であなたに
基本と開集合は
局所化に対応することができます。だから見てください、
これがどれほどクールなのか、あなたは局所化を使っています
開集合が何であるかを定義するために
これらのスペックrを一緒に含める
これらの開集合を形成することができます
スキーム
そしてそれに応じて私たちのカテゴリの
モジュールはカテゴリ準を形成するために接着します
コヒーレンスシート
だから再びこれはすべて、ええ、ピーターの
構成だと思います。素晴らしいですね、どうやって
解析幾何学を構成しますか？同じことをします
ええ
しかし、位相的アーベル群は
アーベルカテゴリを形成しません
これを見ていきます。彼の
濃縮数学の概念を使うことができます
物事を少し良くするために
位相的群を置き換えることができます
これらの濃縮集合で。だからここが
全体のポイントです
ええ、この定義、そう、プロテルサイト
点のプロファイナイトのカテゴリです
これらはカントール集合です
有限の共同主観的なもので
カバーとしての写像の族
したがって、圧縮集合はシーフのようなものです
プロイタルサイト上の集合
再び、私たちはプロ有限で作業しています
ダイヤモンドのためにプロアテル
条件
したがって、同様に圧縮群群は
プロテルサイト上のリングは何でも
そう呼ばれています
圧縮オブジェクトのカテゴリをまとめることができます
圧縮されたオブジェクトの
これはこの全体が
ファンクターであり、ファンクターを取得できます
特定のカテゴリから
それで大丈夫です、あまり深入りしたくありません
これにあまり多くは
したがって、圧縮集合が与えられると、参照できます
tスターをその基底集合として
だから、典型的な例がある
それは、ええと、
実際にどのようにええと、
位相空間からの変化を示しています。tを
位相空間としましょう。
tには、関連付けられた凝縮集合があります。
tバー
そして、それは任意の
プロフィニット集合を連続的な
sからtへの写像の集合に送ることによって定義されます。
これは両方の特性を満たします。ええと、それは
任意の写像に対して意味します。
合成が連続である場合、
それは連続です。
したがって、t下線は凝縮されたええと、あの、
このプロフィニット集合です。
ええ、だから、なぜ私たちはすべてを使っているのか
このプロフィニット条件、まあ、なぜなら
再び、
それは言語の中にあります。私は言いたくないです。
lost in the details so it's in the
language
right it's in the awareness the level of
awareness that you are
right dictates your whole complexity
class
so if and again if these spaces are pro
finite spaces
right then you need to make sure that uh
what do we mean when we say localize we
need to make sure we know what the open
subsets are
and that's why i was using like the
pro-itel site there's you know that's
just one idea there's
lots of ideas how you could model this
but the main takeaway
that i want you know to kind of leave
everybody with is like okay
so what are memories like there is no
同期参照、私たちはどうしていますか
実際に
時間を通過していますね、もしすべての点が
離散化されているなら
あなたは時間を通過しているに違いありません、ええ、あなたは
知っています、通じて
あなたの位置特定を通じてですが、私は試そうとしています
意識レベルを向上させることと
うまくいくこと
あなたは実際に
意識のレベルを向上させることができると思います、もしあなたが
モルフィズムの観点で考え始めることができれば
そして
ええ、モルフィズム間のモルフィズムですから、ええ
あなたは出現する時間現象を得ることができます
プロイタルサイトを使用することによって
そして次に、ダイヤモンドホログラフィック
原理を得ることができます、使用することによって
6つの操作と無限に多くの
そのようなコピーを
ええと、もう一度言うと、あなたはこの色彩的な
タイプをこれらの塔を見て得ることができます
ローカリゼーション
そして、これを時間的な
論理に置くことができるかもしれません、もしかしたら
何が起こっているのかを理解するために
クライブ・ウェアリング、もう一度、どこにいるのか
その意味は何か
うん、そうですね、私はいくつかの
参考文献を挙げて、私はただ
そこで止めるつもりです
素晴らしい、ありがとうございます
もしかしたら、あなたは共有を解除して、私たちは
あなたにいくつかの
質問をしてもっと学ぶことができると本当に嬉しいです
はい、サラ、どうぞ、始めてください
ええ
それは素晴らしい脳の混乱でした、ええと
実際に私はこれを考えているのですが、
これは直接的に来ています
私がこのライブに出る前の哲学
ストリーム
私はトポロジーがどこに位置するのかを見ていました
この哲学の中で、これによって
標準
洞察やスタンフォード百科事典について、そして
私にとって際立っていたのは
モーダルロジック
そして私は自問自答していました
これらの新しい
トポロジーや集合論、またはあなたが
それを行いたい方法のように
私たちは常にこの緊張に直面しています
これらの間で
本当に複雑な
ホメオモルフィック、何でもモルフィックな
私たちの概念化する能力を知っている
これらのモルフィズムと
それらを利用する能力のように
のように
それとも、私たちはこれを本当に作ります
複雑な数学的構造
そして、しかし、ある時点で私たちは
お互いにコミュニケーションをとらなければならないので
私はどんな数学について考えているのか少し疑問に思っています
構造と、そして
もしかしたら特にあなたのものについて、どのように
その構造を見ていますか
収束しているように、戻ってくるように、わかりますか
概念的に、そうしてそれはただ
私たちから逃げてしまわないように
理解する能力において
そうですね、だから私はそう言ったのです、私にとっては
ええと、考えること
あの構造は難しくありません
私はコミュニケーションの部分が
難しい部分だと言えるでしょう
わかりますか、つまり、でもあなたは
子供たちを見てください、彼らはあちこちにいます
場所
そうですね、あなたはここにいると思います
想像して
そして、実際に私はスーパ
共感覚者なので、私のような人にとっては
そうですね、私はそれをすぐに言っただけで、あなたは
それが私にとっておそらく最も簡単なことだと見ました
私にとっては、もしかしたら
置き換える
インクのカートリッジのように、
プリンターの
それは私にとって本当に難しいかもしれませんので、
あなたが言うときは興味深いですね
ええと、どうやってそれを失わないようにするか
だから私は考えます、そしてそれが私が言っていたことです
それはあなたの脳がどこで
成長するかによると思います、私のような人は、私はその
フォントが大好きです、ああ、私は確かに
三つの意識です
私はモルフィズム間の
モルフィズムとモルフィズムについて考えたいです
だから実際、彼らがそうだとは思わない
難しい
私はあなたが知っているように、それは何かのようなものだと思う
それはただの数学であり、ただの
別の言語
あなたが新しい言語を学ぶのが好きな人なら
私は
思う
それに関しては難しさはなく、だから
私は自分が
私にとって、何もないとは思わない
それを妨げるものはない、なぜなら私は何が
悪いか
それを言葉の声明に留めておくことが
その数学がそれを正当化していなければ
ただの文があるだけになるから
ええと、世界は知り得ないものだと言う
またはそのような何かだ、そうだから私は
実際、あなたはただのようなものだと思う
置き換えている
物理学をやっていることを知っているのを置き換える
物理学は本当に難しい
そうですね、まあ、でも仮に言うと
例えば、モトロジックでは彼らが
ちょうど話していたことです
知っていることと仮定することと、あなたが知っていること
だから彼らはこういった接続詞のようなものを持っていました
文の中の部分で、私はつまり
私はわからない、言語は
実際には難しいもので、実際に
数学を
言語に結びつける方法で、私たちが
実際にコミュニケーションできるように
お互いを疲れさせることなく、あなたが知っているように
実際に情報を作り出す
転送することは、あなたが知っているように、一度行くと
信じることから
仮定することに移ると、すべてのこれらの奇妙なものを得る
あなたが知っているような述語や、すべてのこれらの奇妙なものを得る
条件付きのようなもの
実際に数学を持っているということは、あなたのように
これらすべての微妙さと一緒に機能することを知っている
微妙さはまるで
私はどうかわからないけれど、それがどこから来ているのか
私はどうやって
数学を得るのかということです
言語によって押し上げられない
それは面白いですね、でもそれはワクワクしませんか
なぜなら、あなたはあまり知らなかったからです
トポロジーについて、私が言うまで
でもあなたは探求の途中で、あなたは
もっと学んでいます
だから、私はそれが実際には
全く減少しているとは思わない、そうでしょう
いいえ、いいえ、私は必ずしも減少させているわけではなく、私は
言っているのは、ええと
助けを促進する、つまり圧縮すること
言語を圧縮することを知っています
概念を圧縮すること
そうですね、そして私の側では、私はそうではないと思います
それがだと思う
有害かもしれないと思う、それかもしれない
それらを開いて
すべての概念を開いて、何が、ええと、あなたが知っていること
時間は存在しないと思うので、それは
何が急いでいるのか、そうだよね
私は大丈夫だから、あなたが知っていること
つまり
それについての一つの注意点は、ええと、線形の
文字列
話されたり、ポッドキャストやライブストリーム、またはテキスト
そうだね、しばしば不明確だけど
また、それは強制する
いわゆる時間的構造、局所的な
意味的構造の中の統語的な
そして、ええと、これらを見ることを選ぶかどうか
これらの、ええと、関連を
基礎的なもの、これは根のようなもので、これが
成長しているもの
以前の文献のスレッドのように
それが暗い森の中に走り去っていく
文献のことか、それとも実際に
アンカリング
広大な知識の体において本当に
これが面白い
議論、ああ、そうだ、あれはダンスだ
話すので
それが私にとって自然なことはどれほどクールか
数学と文学のようなものだから
あなたは持っている
いくつかの重い哲学者が何かに気づいていた
素晴らしいことに、私は「なぜ」と思う
私たちはただ
彼らが言っていることを強化して、いくつかの
図を使って、見て、私が言うのは簡単だ
ああ、もしかしたらクライヴ・ウォーリングの色彩的
塔は切られている
特定の方法で、数学の部分のように
実際にある
急な学習曲線がある間に
あなたは実際に内部に入ることができる
クライブ・ウェアリングのようにあなたはそうではない
ダニエルが言っているように
ええと、逆行性健忘症ですね
素晴らしい、それは線形の言葉です
あなたは実際に必要な文が必要です
それに入っていく
それは何ですか、そして私は実際に思います
言語
は、実際にそれがあまりにも
圧縮されていると、
そしてそれが実際に透明でない場合、
美しい透明性があります
数学の中に
すべてそこにあります、そして再び数学は
完璧ではありませんよね、そこには
ポイントとは何か、私たちは深刻な
問題を抱えています、あなたは持っています
あなたは述語的で、そしてあなたは知っています
数学にはいくつの定義がありますか
self-referencing is horrible
you know so like math is not to be
worshipped at all and that's why it's
like oh
we should just have all the languages
you can see i talk about everything at
once and i'm like
but that's my synesthete right i think
there's actually the
the beautiful thing about the synesthete
is that maybe you can see
uh like an aerial view of things and i
think for me
i can do a local global just because of
the way my brain works
you know but then i was you know i was
trying because i love everybody's like
differences and i don't want anybody to
be like anybody else and i was trying to
say
うーん、どうやらあなたは多分知っているようですね
時々、私たちは一つの意識であり
時々、私たちは12の意識です
でも、私は本当に、私は本当に興味があります
なぜ
えっと、あなたたち二人がどうかはわからないけど
もし、完全な記憶があるなら
または、記憶があって、あなたは今までに
記憶が突然浮かんできたり、未来の記憶があったり
または、デジャヴ
私はそういうことに本当に興味があります
うん、私はただその
圧縮のことを明確にしたかっただけなんだけど、
圧縮をしばらく擁護したい
普通は、私は同意するだろう、あなたが知っているように
そのことに対する含意は、私はいいえと言う
それは
悪い、たくさんの素敵な
微妙さを捨ててしまうけれど、私は確かに
私の限られた経験の中で感じたことがあります
philosophy i've definitely bumped up
against
um some spots where there have been
words that if you know somebody once
somebody
hits it when somebody puts a noun to a
concept to a word
it's like this fantastic compression
algorithm where it's like oh that's a
concept
somebody had and they put it into a word
and now i can pack it up and
like make some more space in my brain
for other stuff and
i think that is like bad practice
whether it can be in math or or
in words like in whatever mean means you
do
it's it's just it's the best so i'm
always now i'm finding myself like
そのラチェットを探している
知っていて、あなたはそれを愛するでしょう、ではあなたは
数学を愛するでしょうが、それはまるで
すべてが記号だからですが、私は
ただ言っているだけです、はい
圧縮しているのが見えないと思います
少なくとも私のためにはそうではありません
脳のように、私はできません
できない、それはパッケージ化されていない
何かをまとめて、もっとスペースを作ることができるように
他のもののために
でもそれはそうです、なぜならそれはまるで
塔があるので、あなたは脳の中に
塔を保持して、800ページを保持しなくてもいい
そこに到達したページ
誰かが名詞を
概念に置くときのように、反シッター空間のように
うーん、私はそう思います、私にとっては
自分を欺いていると思うでしょう
私はただその言葉を保存しているだけではない
you're storing all the physics
and everything in them you know what do
you what do you think about that um
right
you know this nesting is a topic that
comes up a lot so we talk about nested
markov decision processes how within the
active inference model just
only looking at the mathematics within
this one little clade of math
you can nest those models but then
there's also nesting that's
based upon category theory not my area
but it seems like there's very nuanced
ways of doing
nesting and relationships and so what i
heard with this discussion around
like a sort of a whole total system
shift
upgrade with a dictionary it's like
synergetics and bucky fuller
in that if you understand the interfaces
interfaces between
what these things are currently doing in
the system you can
take them out and like hot swap them
it's like okay it's a graphics card
we could make it a different graphics
card or we could have the same interface
and then improve what's on the other
side of the interface and then it turns
out to be really meta because we're
working on active inference
which is in a way the theory about how
the interfaces work and definitely in
the active inference lab we're taking
a different um approach but it's like
mount everest because
we're you know meeting at different base
camps together
異なる人々と話すために
視点
うんうん、でもそこが
すべてが繁栄する場所だよね、
交差点
そう、それで、うん、見てごらん、
数学がどれだけ強くなるかを、
哲学とぶつけると
逆もまた然り、これらのことや
生物学のどれか
そう、レトログレード健忘症を
色彩の塔にアップグレードして、まるでわお、
君は知っている、だから私は思う、何も
交差点で失われることはない、じゃあ何を
君はさっき言ったのか、
ええと、バッキーが呼んだ出現、君は言った
何かクールなことを
ええと、緊急事態を通じた出現
うんうん、そして彼の緊急事態は、ええと、
生存のたびに
実際に接続するとはどういうことか
あなたが言ったことについてのあなたの、ええ
自然言語の連なりが
努力なしに
アクティブインファレンスでは、私たちはどのように考えるか
行動が続いている
ある意味では、実際に測地線上にある
抵抗が最も少ない道
化学反応のように、たとえそれが
大量の熱と光を放出しても
それが存在する文脈の中で、実際に
最も可能性の高いこと、または最も
エネルギーを放出すること、自由エネルギーが
負であるため、それは散逸する
そして、ええ、それがどのように
散逸が
情報の領域に持ち込まれるか
意味の流れとともに、デルタgのように
意味情報のために、単なる
構文や化学さえもではなく
これはマッピングのマッピングについてです
自由エネルギーを遊牧的な概念として
ある方法または接点で
自由エネルギーを接続する方法です
化学的に特定の実験を展開します
おそらくユニークな予測
そしてその後、構築する数学は
十分一般的です
うまくインターフェースするために、実際にネストします
概念を
ネストされたものに対処できるように
より構文的なシステムを
下位レベルで
量子に降りていき、そして
より高いレベルでの意味論的なものに
目的論的な良さに入って、そうですね、そして
高いレベルでの意味論的なものですね
その後、ホモトピックタイプを呼び出すことができます
色彩的タイプを、そして実際に
すべてのタイプは遊牧的です
まあ、私はそれが好きだよ
何も実際にそうなるまで何もない
広がるので、私もそう思う
あなたはそれが誤った概念だと知っている
動き
もしあなたが実際に考えるなら、あなたが知っているなら
真ん中から始めて広がらない
あなたは知っている、ねえシェイナ、私たちはできるかな
うーん、いくつかのアンカーを設定できるか考えている
いくつかの探求
あなたの質問の一つの周りで、それは
リストにある
うん、ええと、でも私は覚えていない
それが何か
そして、それを投稿するのは技術的に難しすぎるかもしれない
だから、もしあなたができるなら、
選んで
あなたが持ち出している質問の一つを
持ち出している
うん、もう一度共有させて、そして
you tell me which one you like okay okay
this will be like the uh who wants to be
a millionaire
of right this is cool yeah
who wants to be the millionaire back to
the principle should we should we do a
quick
random number generator no pick one
yeah just look at a few and then let's
anchor them and then go
wild whatever one okay so so actually
now
this helps trip my memory so and then
don't forget i have these two
so pick which one maybe i can like make
it
can you see that yeah i can't um
this is something i've been tripping out
on a bit
so and see so measurement
2-2
うん、どこにあるかは知ってるけど、えっと、思ったんだ
2つ目を選ぶかもしれないけど
えっと、それは確実に、どれを選ぶべきか
それを持ってきて下げるのか、それとも
欲しいのか
行こう、私を浅くしないで、見えるよ
みんなの素敵な場所
わかった、何だって言ってるの、何が
測定だよね、うん、やってみて、うん
うん、まあ、えっと、私は
これをたくさん取る傾向があるんだ、私は
たくさんの質問に惹かれていることに気づいている
これらの質問を取り入れて
何らかの具現化された形にして
それが
どうやってそれをやるのか分からない
論文の中で、実際に
卒業する方法で
えっと、これは本当に私にとって興味深い
私は
私は、あなたが知っているように、私たちには
利用可能なものがあり、ツールやこれらすべてがあります
他のもの、これらの一種の義肢
それが私たちに世界を理解させることを可能にします
しかし、私は
私は本当にそれらを
義肢として考えています、そしてある意味で私たちは
私たちは、ええと、世界を理解しています
感じることによって
そして、そして私は、感じることを意味します、
感じるという一つの
あなたはそれが実際に
感情に関連しているかどうか、それは別の
本当に興味深い質問ですが
ええと、保守的でいるために、私はただ
私たちの触覚のような感覚について話しています
そして私たちは
これらすべての利用可能なものを使って私たちの
戦術的な感覚を増強します
でも、それについて考えるのは本当に興味深いです
例えば
このすべての客観的測定について
科学やその他のことにおいて
それが実際にどのように関連しているのか
私たちの具現化された
それは私たちにとって真実ではないでしょう、ある
レベルで、私たちがそれを理解できるまで
具現化された
レベルで意味を成すことができるまで
それがあるというのは、つまりそれがあったということです
哲学において私が持っていた別の種類のフック
でも
ええと、何だったか本当に思い出せません
今はそれが何かということですが、それは
私にとって生きているので、あなたがそれについて
何か考えを持っているかどうかわかりません
ええ、私はすごく影響を受けているので
そうですね、ええと
あなたに、私は分離するつもりです
感情的な
非合理的なものから、私は信じていないように
それと、ええ、彼らは両方とも
同じくらいそこにいる、そう、合理性は
まるで
感情的な、ええ、ガイダンスシステムのようなものだから、そうだね
私が言うとき
私が測定とは何かと言うときのように
私はただ言っている、たくさんのことがある
それに関して、あなたは知っていると言う
これが光の固定速度です
そしてこれがこれで、だから測定は
それはただ保持されているように見える
特定の条件まで、そう、これは
これが光の速度です、私が
あなたの周囲の空間を変えるまで
そう、もしあなたがトーラスに住んでいたら、またはもしあなたが
クラインボトルに住んでいたら、もしあなたが
他の何かに住んでいたら
私はあなたに約束する、あなたは違うものを持っているだろう
光の速さ、それはただの
数学における照明問題
奇妙な空間が与えられ、そこに
点光源を置くと
すべての光線を追跡したらどうなるか
そうですね
実際の形のすべての点が当たるか
実際にはそうではありません、非常に
複雑な空間の場合はそうなります
私にとって、どれくらいの距離が
測定
保持され、メトリクスは再び、私はとても
ファンなので
トポロジーやシーブやそのようなものの
このメトリックは
実質的ではないようです
そうですね、それは私が言ったように
エージェント間の相互主観的合意に基づいています
だから、あなたが言うとき、ええと、
私は、あなたの質問が何か確信が持てません
それは客観的なのか主観的なのかということですか
ここでのすべての測定は
主観的だと思います
そうですね、実際の問題があります
測定において、もしあなたが
厳格なコペンハーゲン主義者であれば、そしてそのような
ことです
そうですね、だから引用されるべき存在は何もないはずです
すべてがその自由な形の中にあるなら
重ね合わせの
実際に測定するとはどういうことか
実際にそのものを制限することなく
そのものを
そして、もしあなたが測定を行うなら、それは誰のためのものですか
重ね合わせを
一つの状態に押し込むなら、私はそれを測定しました
そうですね
それが何を意味するのかわからないし、また
すべての観測者が
去ってしまうとき、
the the thing that was measured goes
back into its original state
so that's why i said like what is a
measurement and chris and i are always
talking about this
right that that assumes that you are
somehow independent of the thing that
you're measuring
and i don't know how to actually do that
right i don't really know what a
boundary is because if you zoom into
your arm
we could take like an electron
transmission microscope and i'd be able
to zoom into your arm in like two
seconds so where'd the boundary go
you know where is the boundary and that
i i'm i'm very perplexed because the
boundary in mathematics is like some
kind of
アシンポート右、あなたのような酸とは何ですか
知っている、だからあなたは一種の、ええと、
アシンポートと、それが私たちが
測定と呼んでいるものです
あなたはバスのようなもので、これはこの長さです
私がバスにたくさんの
時間をかけるまで、または私が
バスにガソリンを注いで燃やすまで、あなたは
私が言っていることがわかりますか、ではその
測定はどれくらい持続しますか、そうですね、私はそれが好きです
それで、
だからあなたは、そう、私は考えていなかった
文脈や感情についてそれほど
私は確かに
それは固定されたものです、だからそれが
考えるのに役立ちます、本当に
誰にとって固定されているのか、その
瞬間のために固定されているのか、でも
そうですね、すべてが自由落下していて、
あなたは見ます
um i really think there is nothing
periodic here i think there is no
repetition
right we have to actually account for
like what leap year or something right
because the calendar is off
so i'm i'm really uh i'm really
impressed that in
our like in everybody's free fall and
you know what the earth is
going a thousand miles an hour east
right and that if everything is rotating
your own cells are popping in and out
where is the measurement i'm not sure
nothing is fixed
so it's very silly to think that i have
this measurement it's like if you only
knew
that you were actually working over
discrete time
その瞬間、あなたがいた瞬間
バスを測っていると、もうそこにはいない
そう、それが私が非常に非常に
興味を持っていることです
5分前にバスを測りましたが
それは同じバスですか
いいえ、そしてそれが何を意味するのか分かりません
それが、実際に何を
測っているのかということです、私たちは不適切な言葉を測ることができます
その物の多くのコピー
しかし、あなたはその測定が
その物の反映であると言わなければなりません
それが、私が
時間的部分の作業について好きな一つのことです
それはバスです
昨日、それは本当に今日のバスですか
分かりません、そして私はいつもそう思っていました
常に困惑していました、あなたは知っています
同じ空間に目を覚ます
しかし、本当にそうなのか、私は本当に確信がありません
それで、えっと、それは
あなたは知っていますが、ええ、境界について私は本当に
境界に興味があり、そしてどのように
実際にそれらが、ええ、
どのように機能するのか、私は本当に
それが機能するかどうか確信が持てません、つまり明らかに私は
手を
ガラスに当てることができますが、それはただの
このスケールでのことです
そうですね、だから私はただ言っているのは、
測定
もしあなたが測定と言うつもりなら
それなら、あなたは本当に正確である必要があります
ええ、時間は関与していません、何も
これも関与していません、それはただの瞬間です
バン、この測定は
瞬間に保持されます、なぜなら明日誰が知っているか
そして、測定棒はどうなっているのか
ええ、量子のようにたくさんのものがあります
機械的に、流星棒は機能しません
exist anyway
so so i don't even know how to use all
these freaking
philosophical labels but i want to ask
if your ambition in
in trying to apply uh topology a kind of
a paradigm
is to arrive at some form of realism or
are you
interested in i mean i'm kind of
wondering what your ground is in terms
of like
yeah what would be the what's the end
goal
in terms of like what would be the
perfect math in your mind like where
would it take you
right yeah well i'm after those grain
unified theories right so i'm after the
i'm after the unifying the grand unified
粒子の理論を持つ物理学
私が思うに数学の統一理論
実際に考えている
数学の理論は物理学を包含している
だからこそ私が「やあ」と言っているのが見える
数字のようなものを見てみませんか
ブラックホールの理論的バージョン
そんな感じのもの
なぜなら私は壮大なものの中で考えているから
数学の統一理論
私はすべてを手に入れるつもりです、なぜなら私は
スーパーテックマークのような
ええとレベル4だけど、あなたはあなたが
すべてを手に入れることになる、あなたは手に入れることになる
あなたは何を手に入れることになるのか
ああ、そうだ、それが私が「おお」と言った理由です
現実をただのものとして呼んでいるのですか
この小さな瞬間を覚えておかなければなりません
私は意識の中で信じているから
私の目標は
actually partition
the brain partition the consciousness so
that you can actually experience
everything at once again i don't believe
in linear time i don't think it goes
linearly
and i'm really baffled why the brain
only does that
and i think it does not because i know
when you're freshly formed like
um a baby it's very it's such a
beautiful being because
you know she's like a little portal i'm
like where did you come from
you know like the very act of birth is
something interesting because it seems
like it's something that got through the
interface
right where did this little portal come
from and i'm actually
i'm not so interested in the mechanics
of the interface i'm interested in
breaking through the interface taking
off the interface and trying another one
because again i think that the 20
fundamental numbers and everything that
you're subjected to here
and the laws of physics or whatever are
just purely interface-based which i
which i think is a mathematics concept
it would be so rad if we were all able
to take off the interface of this
complexity
of our current complexity and quote go
somewhere else
i don't mean milky way i don't mean that
i mean leave this interface all together
of three times of three space and one
time
and go find a different modulized space
right and that's what i'm trying to do
with i'm like oh if you could actually
partition
consciousness right because it seems
like i don't know if y'all had like
general anesthesias or like
if you've ever fainted or anything um i
have a like a few times just from like
kind of intense things but
i remember something remained
it's like you might have wiped out the
consciousness by general anesthesia
right but you didn't take away the
awareness and that's what i was very
curious about
that something was still there and so uh
you know don hoffman and like me it's
like
i'm actually interested in what that
space is right
the kind of talky sensory thing like i
can see that as an apparatus
but i'm sorry i'm interested in like the
divinity whatever the infinity not in a
religious sense but like
what actually transcends this because i
don't think anything here is like real
at all
you know so when people say what's your
baseline reality well it's not this
i'm really always curious to get in the
dream space i'm really always curious
to quote sleep because when i'm asleep
who's asleep
oh your body is not a sleeve right
because you would you know die
so i'm really curious in the states that
are actually
i guess i could say it like this i'm
trying to take subjectivity
インターフェースから出て、それを
異なる設定に置く
私は主観性を持たないつもりです
体ができることだけに制限されている
なぜなら、たくさんの痛みがあるからです
痛みは人々を
体の中に留めると私は思いますが、
実際には他の誰かのようになれるかもしれません
だから、もし主観性をそのまま
探求することができれば
それが私が数学が得意だと思うことです
本当に良いことをするのは、もし私が
持つことができれば
あなたは、ああ、みんなで考えましょう
同時に、例えば
もしあなたが知っているなら、もし私たちが
実際にここにいて、さらに
あなたは、ケンブリッジの使徒会議にもいるとしたら
それは人々を困惑させます
なぜなら、あなたはこれを持っているからです
imagination right we're able to talk and
you're you know i can say
oh sarah david let's imagine like we're
in hawaii swimming with the you know the
sea turtles
you can go there just like that what is
that why can you do that
what is that imaginary space so i
actually think we're actually
really gifted creatures and you have
this beautiful tool
called the imagination which has not
been fortified
so what i'm trying to do is actually put
the imagination
in its own little hogwarts school right
like when you're young you're able to do
plays and you're doing all those things
then you go up and it's like taxes and
like that
そして、実際に私たちがいるのは
創造的であるためで、あなたはすべてを見ることができます
私が好きな哲学者たちは
バイタリストです
そう、私は存在することは創造であると思います
だから、私はここにいると思うことができます
私たちは新しいものを創造するためにここにいます
理論を作り出し、
インターフェースを突破するために
今、私は人々にバスの前に飛び込むように言っているわけではありません
それが私が言っていることではありません
そう、私は言っています
それを覗いてみるのはクールだと思います
ちょうど、
新しい赤ちゃんが生まれるように、私は
誕生に困惑しています、誰もそれを説明できません
そして、あなたは何かがどのように
突破したのか全くわかりません、
そう、インターフェース、だから私が求めているのは
それで、私は使っています
ああ、とても美しい数学
私は思う、人生はとても神聖であり
とても美しく、そうあるべきだ
ええと、支えられ、そしてああ説明されるべきだ
同じくらい洗練された数学的な
構造によって、私は本当にこの
最も単純なバージョンが最良だとは思わない
それについてはわからない、実際には私は思う
洗練されたものは
哲学的に同じくらい
数学的に洗練されるべきだ
そうすれば、相乗効果と調和が得られる
そして実際に
それから実際に一粒を説明できる
統一理論
なぜなら私は本当に思う、ああ、私は知っている、もし
すべてが
ダイヤモンドであるなら、私は本当にそう思う
あなたは知っている、たくさんの
私は思う、もしこの現実が一つのようなら
ダイヤモンドのモジュラー空間に行けるなら、
簡単に新しいモジュライズされた
空間にジャンプできる。
そんなに難しくないよ、わかるでしょ？
それがあなたのように聞こえるかどうかわからないけど、
この小さな人は誰だろう、ああ、そうだ、私は
完全に探検家のようなもので、私はこう言うだろう。
意識のバスに乗り込んで、
物を見に行こう。
これはただのこれではない、ただの
何かを知っている、あなたの
意識は決して離れず、
それに入るのは素晴らしい、
その空間に入るのは、わかるでしょ、実際に
そう、
ここに持ってくることができれば、
実際に意識の空間を
ここに持ってくることができれば、あなたは実際にもっと
共感覚的だと思う、わかるでしょ、
ああ、そうだ、私はどこから始めればいいのかわからない。
スキルが終わり、脳は
ホログラム自体のようです。だから、
すべてはあなたの中央プロセッサーが
ホログラムです。
それが何について本当に好奇心をそそるのか
この空間は
あなたは知っていますか
私は確かに脳が
こんな風だとは思わない、もちろんあなたは
頭を打たれたくない
明らかに、でもそれは恐ろしい能力を持っています。
書き換える
そう、それはスーパーハミングコードのようです。
あなたは脳の中にエアコレクティングコードを持っています。
明らかに生物を
生かすために
あなたは知っていますが、ええと、私はあなたが知っていると思います。
ようなものを考え出すために
あなたは知っています、リーマンゼータのような
関数がブラックホールのようです。そういうのが
cool
so i'm just kind of trying to upgrade uh
you know find what is the essence of
things and it's like oh is it math what
is this
you know ah the essence
i'll ask one question which is how how
would you imagine
that this insight or this set of
upgrades potentially being taught to
advanced or younger
students could change research or
practice because i noticed words like
descent condition definability
decidability
completeness of course so where do the
sort of everyday usages of these terms
come into play with how we can rethink
them based upon a new level of
mathematical rigor
oh that's such a great question yeah i'm
such an advocate for like new models of
pedagogy
right because i think the way
mathematics is taught now is horrible
and it makes you know everyone uh
frightened it's like you're taught
calculus first
before logic before topology
before any of it right and so it seems
like
you know you there people are not using
the apostle book that should be the only
book used for calculus
um yeah so if you actually if you taught
a category theory straight you know from
the bottom up
imagine the beautiful connections that
would be able to be made
cross-disciplinary you can see that one
私の主な目標の一つは、人々に
お互いに話すことです
数学者に物理学者と話すようにさせて
哲学者と話すようにさせることです
ええ、カテゴリーを通じて考えると、
理論的にこれを自然に体現するでしょう
共感覚的思考、これは私が
擁護しようとしているものです
なぜなら、非線形のような人々がいるからです
私のような思考者は簡単に
排除され、彼女は
交差点で働いていると言われましたが、彼女は
一つのトピックに真剣ではないと
私は思っていますが、
一つのトピックは
他のトピックの反映です、すべてがダイヤモンドのようなとき、
だから私にとって、もしあなたが
これらの美しい言葉を紹介しているなら、
ああ、
降下条件のように、もしあなたが始めるなら
カテゴリー理論から
非常に最小限に構築されていて
のみ
必要なものを追加できる
自分の空間を構築するために
そう、あなたはできる
構築することができると言えるでしょう
自分自身の
アイデアに従って構築するために
別のアイデアを取り、それを彫刻するのではなく
人工的に物を追加すること
カテゴリー理論の良いところは
これらの限界がすべて構築されていることです
実際の
ええと、理論自体から始めているわけではなく
何かを追加して、さらに追加して
さらに追加して、そして取り去って
それが分析なのか、それとも
こういうことなのか
だから、これらすべてがあることがわかります
ペーターショーのような方法
再構築するような、ええと
可換としての関数解析
代数が超送信された席
なぜなら、あなたがしていることは、まるで取るようなものだから
あなたが違いだと思っていたもの
そして実際にはそれを同じにしている
ことなので、私は非常に包括性と
歓迎の支持者です
多くの思考の流れがあり、もし
みんなが「おお」と言ったら
ねえ、それはただのように見える
このモルフィズムと、これは
このモルフィズムのように見える
実際には研究を助けることになるでしょう
みんなが一緒に働くことになるから
あなたは新しいことを想像できますか
解毒剤と
ええと、私はメンタルヘルスの
支持者で、ええと、なぜなら、ええと、あなたは知っている
there's been a lot of stuff like
i don't know i'm sure everyone has had
you know elderly family members go
through some you know horrible
neurodegeneration and i am not satisfied
with the way that the brain is being
modeled
and i'm like you know if you actually
were using the morphisms or the
chromatic tower idea
maybe you would be able to understand
what's actually going on in somebody you
know
um and we'd be able to relate to them
empathically
instead of just like this like clear-cut
medicinal thing well they'll never be
good again they lost their memory
well we can you know no i don't think
it's something that can be lost
let's just try to reconstruct the
morphisms you know
so there's like there's so many things
that i'm
after with this one is unifying all
these branches that are working
against each other it's like when the
mathematicians and the physicists
honestly work together right if if they
can
and not have a bunch of egos in the way
then the beauty that results you get
these beautiful
grand unified theories because it's like
we're meant to be inclusive and
everybody to help each other and so
everybody knows that like i'm you know
not an advocate for these like
standardized tests and i'm gonna test
you and i'm better than you
そして、なぜ人々をテストするのかわからない
みんなより優れているために
実際に私たちは物事に取り組むことができる
こんな感じで
私はそれが、ええと、完全に
教育学を革命的に変えるだろうと思うし、それは
提供する
未来のモデル、つまり何が何かの
ホグワーツの学校がどのように見えるかということだと思う、なぜなら
その時
あなたは実際に、はい、私たちは持っている
想像力を
それは贈り物であり、あなたが持っている贈り物です
これ
そして、私が試みていることを通じて、私が
ここでやっていることは、非常に
数学を学ぶことに対する創造的なアプローチです
そしてそのようなこと
だから、あなたは実際に
数学に歓迎されたのです
自分を表現することが少ない人々は
クリエイティブな人々
私もこのアートスクールで教えているんだよね
そして彼らはいつもこう言うんだ
私は最高の数学の才能がないし
でもあなたの視覚的スキルを見てごらん
ある意味で彼らは
ほとんど同じなんだ
だから私はたくさんの
美しさがあると思う、それはダイヤモンドのようで
こういったことは教えられてきた
とても早い段階で、あるいは全ての人に
あなたが知っている多くの人々にとって
これを研究に統合できれば
そうすれば、私はただ思うんだ
みんなが一緒に働くことには美しさがある、私は
あまり競争心の強い人間ではないんだよね
どうやって想像できるか思い出させてくれた
その方法は
ああ、そのアート
could actually inform math rather than
the reverse
like not not just art but like improv
improvisation improvisational arts upon
somebody's drawing just free form
and if you could figure out a dynamic
mapping of like oh you're actually
talking about
this this kind of logic and you don't
and you're drawing it but you're not
you're not putting it to you know you
don't even know that you mean that but
you mean that
that is actually kind of fascinating
look how beautiful that is yeah i just
got accepted to what you just said is um
you know i'm an advocate for pedagogy in
the creative settings so
i'll do i'll do uh you know experiments
like that all the time
like their their topic is to design
a four-dimensional university like i
want a four-dimensional university i
want a gymnasium featuring flying
lessons
right and i want a library and um i want
you to talk about adinkras or dinkers or
james gates air correcting codes
these students right have minimal
mathematics skills but they are
in their learning analysis geometry and
topology
to actually make a structure that can
hold flying lessons they're actually
having to teach themselves
a four dimensional coordinate grid
that's not euclidean this is not
euclidean at all it's differential
geometry
right it's bumpy and i said you know
それは四次元で、彼らは
ハイパーボリュームしか持っていないからです
それがどれほど素晴らしいか、あなたがそれを知っているのは、
まるで、ええと、
私にとっては、それがとても悲しいことです、
それは非常に排他的だからです
あなたが知っているように、エクセターアカデミーのように、
このハークネスメソッドを持っているので、私がすることは、
ハードネスメソッドを取り入れて、
どこでもそれを話します、私はそれを教えます
カリフォルニア州立大学で教え、ここでも教え、
あちこちで
そして、ええ、その方法は、
概念をシナジェティックに示すことです、
そのように、
そして、あなたが知っているように、最小限の
指導を与えるだけで、彼らは数学を学んでいます、
自分自身で、
だから、ええ、それはあなたが知っているように、私は
興味があります
他の人々が実験したいと思っている
章を学ばないということのように
一つ
これは三角形です、誰も知らない
そのように学ぶのは、方法があるからです
実際に学ぶのは
ええと、統合することです、だからなぜ
学生たちはそんなに問題を抱えているのか
単語問題を解くのに多くの問題がある
なぜなら彼らはこれらを教えられてきたからです
科目は別々に、これらの科目は
全く別々ではありません
彼らは統合的に教えられるべきです
ホリスティックな方法で
そしてあなたは完全に正しい、サラ、方法は
ホリスティックな方法を得ることです
ええと、消化しやすいのは
創造的な方法で、私は学生たちに見せました、
ええと、この素晴らしいコンピュータプログラマーが
4次元ルービックキューブを解いている
私はそれを再現すると言ったが、実際に彼らは
ああ、四次元はこれをどうするのか、ああ
これはテストです
ああ、それはそれほど多くの面を持っているので、ずっと簡単です
非常に線形なレッスンよりも
これは四次元空間で、ああ、あなたが
知っている、私は思う
私は思う、ええと、あなたがもし
私のように直感的で、ほとんどの数学が
この直感的な空間から来ているなら、あなたは
その直感的な空間を尊重する必要があり、私は
本当にそれが軽視されていると思うので、そこには
ラマヌジャンのような数学者がいて、
そんな感じで、彼は言っている
このアイデアがどこから来たのかわからない
それはただこれから来たもので、あなたはそれを知っている
本当に押しやられることがある
だから、でも私はこれの多くが
先見の明のあるものだと思う
あなたは知っている、ええと、そういうものから来る
特定されていない空間
そして、ああ神様、私は人々の
創造的な空間を育てます
やってみるとどれだけ多くのアイデアが出てくるか見てください
何かのような
そのような楽しいアイスブレイカーですね
私が会議や何かを主催するたびに
あなたは知っています
私は、ええと、まあ、あなたは知っています
私たちが、あなたは知っている、想像してみてください
ええと、あなたは知っている、ワニのようなものです、だから私は
人々を持っています
空間を変える、もしあなたが変えたら、ああ、あなたは
爪を持っていたら、あなたは何をしますか
これらの爪で、あなたは知っています
だから、もしあなたがなんとか
揺さぶることができれば
あなたは知っています、ええと、リールを回して
何かを作り出す、ええと
想像上のようなものだと思います
imagination is more real
so for somebody like me i privy the
imaginary space because like this pin
i think there was an idea of a pin
before the pin so the pin is okay in my
opinion but i still think the imaginary
space
trumps everything right you had to have
the idea of the car i
want to have the idea of the thing so i
put a lot of my efforts into nurturing
like students imaginary space you know
so oh my god yeah infusing
like having uh you can teach math in a
creative way
and that's why i'm so excited that there
are these people like me you know i
write books and it's like
oh it's like i'm going to write i'm
going to write
あなたは知っていますか、ええ、私は女の子を書くつもりです
そしてダイヤモンド
私はこのオープニングラインが好きです、これは私のようなものです
新しい本は、彼女が
砂時計の中で眠っているようなものです
なぜそうしないのですか、だからそれがあなたが
とにかくやっていることです
そしてそれは、ああ、ガラスを通して何ですか
それは何ですか
だから私は実際にあなたに形を与えることができます、私は
その形を創造的にあなたに紹介できます
そして私は実際にあなたに言うことができます
その形についての定理ですが、私は
定理から始めませんでした
そう、私はこの粗い
直感的なアイデアから始めました
実際にそれには質感があったので
人々は、砂時計の中で眠るのはどんな感じですかと尋ねます
神よ
私は砂に食べられるのですか、私はその
砂は誰かが私をひっくり返すのか
時間が切れたときに何が起こるのか
あなたは知っている、そして、ええと、人々の
自己内省を通じて、私は本当に
しっかりした思考者を得る
それが私の求めているものです、私は
人々が暗記したり、書いたりすることを求めていません
テスト
もちろんテストは難しいですが
それは
何人の人がその資料を覚えているか
後で、あなたは私が何を意味しているか分かりますか、
だから、暗記は私が求めているものではありません
私は実際に構築することに興味があります
内面的な空間、独立した学習者の内面的な空間
考えることができ、
クロスリファレンスできる人々
なぜなら、私は再び言うでしょう
私は常にあなたの最も強力な
思考者たちだと言います
are thinkers who can think along all of
those intersections right
you know if there's a problem like the
rover crashes
yeah you need your cs people but you
also need your physics people you need
your math people and that's why
you know uh normally those research
groups have that
i don't know and daniel you may have
that too right in your labs
i bet you have people from all
disciplinaries working on the inference
stuff right
species of every type of insect um well
our approach with active inference lab
is provide the affordance and the
opportunity
to co-design and wherever people are at
in learning about active inference or
関連するトピックに興味があるか、
それをいくつかの
分野で適用したいと思っていると、
真ん中で出会い、
アクティブインファレンスを
統一的な
トピックとして、そして橋として使うために、ええと、
それが、
本当に、あなたがここにいる理由です。なぜなら、私たちが
実際に交差することができたからです。
アクティブインファレンスが私に来て、これらの
他のアイデアと、あなたが言ったことは、
本について、
バッキー・フラーのテトリスを思い出させました。
スクロールは、
ゴルディロックスと三匹のクマについてですが、
彼ら四人は四面体です。
それで、四面体がどのように
最小のシステムであるかについて話しています。
そして、これらの四面体のジョークがたくさんあります。
埋め込まれているもので、それはまるで
実践と物語を通じて学ぶこと
キャラクターやドラマを通じて
これらすべての創造的な次元
私たちが実際に生成的であることを可能にする
いわゆる中で
代替的だが、今日の代替的なファッションは
明日の、知っての通り、時代遅れであり
そしてレトロ
それはただ歴史的なもので、私たちはどうやって
厳密さを尊重するか
この非常に根本的なものとして
相互主観的な
エージェントについて話しているように
異なる視点を持ちながらも
また、私たちはローカルな論理が必要で、それは
まったく不調和ではないから
そのため、私たちが話しているとき
私たちを支えるシステムについて
ええ、私たちはそれらが持続する必要があるので、どうやって
どうやって
どうやってそれをするのか、それが私の質問です
私たちは厳密さとその種のものを統一します
ほぼ超越的、あるいは少なくともそうでない場合
普遍的なもの、そんな感じのものと
相互主観的
死すべき者の次元での定義は正しい
そして実際にあなたは
私の講演の中で、私はあなたに
何らかの緩い地図を非常に特定的に与えませんでした
そうですね、私は実際にはかなり
その点で才能があると思います。おそらくそれが私が
こんなに早く雇われた理由です
それは
私はアイデアを
創造的な方法で紹介することができる
しかし、私はあなたがそれを完全に理解できるように絶対的な厳密さを与えます
あなたがそれを徹底的に知ることができるように
そうですが、私はあなたに十分な厳密さを与えて
その対象を知ることができるようにしますが、私はあなたにも授けます
with the creativity to be able to
intersect it somewhere else
else so we all say the mortal plane
right but you won't really be aware
when you pass away and you already could
have you can't prove that you exist
anyway
right so i'm like yes respect your life
force
yeah but don't ever think that you're
not infinite
because there's no proof that you aren't
right so like there's this structure
like
there is no structural causality you
know you go somewhere but you will never
be aware of it
and i all i always say uh when people
ask me that how do we how do we take
your your lovely um
あなたは自分の素敵な、ええと、あなたが知っているような
高次の次元からの素晴らしいもの
そしてそれらをここで扱うようにしていて、私は
高次の次元はここにあるように思う
あなたはそれらの中にいる
そう、それはあなたの外にあるわけではない
あなたは知っているように、あなたはまさにその
宇宙から生まれている
それはすべてあなたの中にあり、私はそれがちょうど
私が言おうとしていたときのことを思い出す
あなたが実際に気づくことはありますか、あなたが
通り過ぎるとき、だからあなたはそうならない
そう、それは奇妙で、それは
非常に奇妙です
だからそれはこのような行き詰まりのように見える
制限するもの
あなたの想像上の
空間をより価値あるものにするために
私は知っている、私が眠ろうとしているとき、私は
ええと、
i'm like i'm gonna i'm gonna actually be
aware when i actually go to sleep you're
not
right when you go to sleep you just you
wake up right you're never actually like
aware of the moment you go to sleep
right and i'm like oh that's very
strange what is this awareness phenomena
right so yeah there is the uh i and so
when people call it mortal plane i guess
i call it the interface
that's one possible interface but again
babies can breach through it and i also
think there's other ways of getting
other interfaces yeah so how you balance
the rigor is that well
i'm giving you some of the top
mathematics like on the planet yeah
so that rigor you have to be yeah for
your own integrity
教育者として、そして知識人として
もちろん、あなたはそうです
あなたは地球をより良くするためにここにいます
皆のために、だからあなたはすでに
あなたは、ええと、あなたの主題に敬意を表するための誠実さを持っています
あなたの主題に
だから、あなたの主題に敬意を表するために、あなたは学びます
それを完璧に、はい
しかし、あなたはまた、それに関する
物語があることを知ることもできます、あなたは厳密さを学びます
しかし、あなたはまた、どのように厳密さを学ぶかを
創造的にすることができ、非常に
単純な暗記を通じてである必要はありません
右、カテゴリーとしての
オブジェクトとして、もしあなたがそれを非常に
美しい方法で学ぶなら
それなら、私もそれを尊重しますので
それが私が創造的な
設定について言いたいことです
私は決して、ああ、はい、ここにこれがあるとは言いません
ダイヤモンドのこと、それだけです
いや、実際には非常に具体的ですが、それは
私が話している相手によると
もしそれがすごく、ええと、あなたのようなものであれば
数学者はすでにこの
レベルから始めます
そうですね、もし私がそれを
学部生に紹介するなら、私は
直感的な
ええと、直感的な、ええと、私は
そのことの導関数を知らない
実際に彼らをそれに導入します
なぜなら、彼らにそれを保持してほしいからです。私は
彼らにシャットダウンしてほしくないし、彼らの
コルチゾールシステムを引き起こしたくないので、
私は本当に
メタ認知的な
技術の支持者です。だから、
一度、私は本当に良い
感覚を得て、どのように人々が学ぶかについて
分かると思う瞬間
私のように非常に抽象的な
何かの交差点を投げてください
そして、あなたがする方法で正しく理解します
バランス
厳密さと創造性は、誰が
実際の学習者であるかを知ることです
そう、彼らが誰であるか、そしてそれはほぼ
私の教育法は
ハープのようで、私はハープを調整しています
なぜなら、私自身がハープだからです。だから、
実際にバランスを取る方法は
厳密さ
と創造性は、自分自身が
ハープのようであることです。そうすれば、私は
実際の学生に調整できます
ああ、彼らはもっと創造的です。私はこうしてみます
ああ、彼らはもっと
エンジニアですか、
私はエンジニアリングを試みます。私は試みます
システムの方法は正しい
私はただ、ええと、ダイヤモンドを説明するんです
コンピュータサイエンスの人たちの集まりのように
それをデータ構造に変えたので
もし私が何かと整合させることができれば
彼らがすでに知っていることと
私にとって、学ぶことは
頭の中に星座を持つことだと思います
あなたはどれだけの星座を持っていますか、ええと
実際にすべてをリンクできますか
一緒に
だから、もし私が、もしあまりにも多すぎるなら
引用の厳密さ
創造的な
設定なしで、ええと、
私は、私は人々を失敗させると思います
まだ星座を持っていない人たちを
専門家の集まりもそれをすることができるかもしれませんが
でも、ええと、誰も知らない
誰も意識の領域を知らない
nobody knows what this actually is
and at least i'm open to saying that
every theorem i come up with
it's just a theorem some people think
they're absolutely right and i really
don't agree with that like at all
we have rough ideas of what it means to
do this and this but that's why i'm
asking like
what actually are the fundamental units
of life you know you can tell me when
the interface breaks
but you can't tell me about awareness
and like if i asked a neuroscience like
why can i not split the consciousness
right they would say well you know i
don't know
you know because i'm not talking about
like i'm not talking about partitioning
the brain
そして、あなたはただ二つ持っているようなものです、それはまるで
まるで分割画面を見るようなものです
古い映画のような、私はそれについて話しているのではありません
それについてではなく、実際に話しているのは
について
ダブル体験、ダブル体験
トリプル体験、しかしただの感覚的なものではなく
あなたは知っています
だから、私はあなたが
厳格さと創造性のバランスを取る方法は
自分自身に対しても誠実であることだと思います
主題に対しての誠実さ
ええ、実際にそれを学びたい人は誰でも
私は特定のことを学びたいのです、そうでしょう
でも、もしあなたが持っていない場合はどうしますか
創造性
あなたは決してどこにも行けないでしょう
私があなたに与える厳格さで、もしあなたがただ
厳格であれば、あなたはただそこにいるだけです
しかし、もし私があなたに創造性を植え付けることができれば
and you're actually going to be able to
take the rigor and link it
and intersect it and again if so it's
all about like
why you think you know your
phenomenological like state
i think we're here to create new things
i think being is creation
so if i can give you rigor but it can
also
hold your imaginary space then you'll be
able to take that idea like nobody else
but me would take diamonds and apply
them to consciousness
you know what i mean right so we're
getting close to
close to the end of the hour but maybe
um i'm kind of curious about about what
um
what started you in math like like how
昔のあなたは
ああ、完全に若かった、まあ私は「うーん」と思っていた
あなたは知っている、私は、ええと、私は「これは何だろう」と思っていた
物事、あなたが言いたいことはわかる
私は鏡を見つめていて、私はこう思っていた
それは本当に興味深い、そしてそれから
ええと、私は基本的に両親に尋ねていた
なぜ私は床を突き抜けないのか
床
あなたは知っている、私はかなり早い段階で理解した
これらすべてのものが
なんとなく同じものでできているように見えた
そして私は「なぜあなたは」
なぜ私は床を突き抜けないのか、
何がこれを
一緒に保っているのか
彼はまた、なぜ私が
同じものの中で目を覚ましたのか非常に好奇心が強い、私は「なぜ」
私は明日ロブスターではないのかと思った、だからここには
私がいた何らかの安定性があった
非常に困惑している
私も熱心な読者で、あなたが
読むとき、頭の中に声があるような感じがする
読書中で、私は「誰だろう？」と思った
人々が自分自身に話しかけているとき、誰がそれなのか
それが誰なのか
あなたもわかると思うが、私は非常に意識していた
あなたが眠っているとき
誰が眠っていたのか、誰も眠っていなかった、もし私が
夢や物事を思い出していたら
こんな感じで
だから非常に鮮明だった、わかるだろう、私は
たくさんの
動物とのつながりを持っていた
そして、ええと
体が入れ替わるようなことではなく、それは
非常に非常に共感的だった
ええと、私は訪れていた、ええと、いわば
神聖な場所に行って、これは
ワクワクすることだと思った
そして、私が見つけたのは、ええと、あなたも知っているように
熱心な読者
すでに文学的な空間を持っていたが、私は
これらは何だろうと思った
私はいつも何かがあると思っていた
他の何かがあって、だから私が好きなのは
数学
そう、それはそれは
ええと、この美しい言語であり、贈り物で
実際に私に考えさせてくれた
ええと、より高い世界について、あなたも知っているように
構造的な方法で
そして、私は「おお、これは実際の言語だ」と思った
実際の言語
そして、私は何かがあると思った
普遍的なものがあると思ったが、そうではない
方言があまりない
数学には、あなたも知っているように、そしてそれは本当に
シンプルにした、ああ、あなたも知っているように、カテゴリ理論
ねえ、私はやる
自分で教えていたようなもの
中国語と私の
カリフォルニアのこのアクセントがまだあることを知っています
アクセントのようなものがあって、それはうまくいかなかった
あまりうまくいかなかった
そして方言は実際に害を及ぼすことがある
言語だけど
ええ、数学はこの普遍的なもののように思えた
方法で、ああ、もしかしたら私たちは
すべて
このものが何であるかを理解できるかもしれない
再び数学はそうではなくて、それは
私の数学のバージョンは非常に
哲学的で、だからそれは
うーん、私のお気に入りの作家はあなたのような人でした
アリス・イン・ワンダーランドを知っていて、私は
ああ、鏡の国のアリスのような、それは
クールで、最後には彼がすべての
三段論法をやっている
そして私は、もしあなたがそのようなものを取るなら
すごいことを知っている、ああ
三段論法をいじくり回すことができる
それと因果関係をいじくり回していた
パラドックスやそのようなことを知っているから
すごく熱心な読者で、手に入れることができる
大きな哲学
とても若くて、オープンでいることも
何があるのか、なぜなら私は言えるから
その時は線形ではなくて、私はそう思った
主題が必要だ
でも実際にこれをすべて解決できる
時間のように、それは線形ではない、どうやって
それをして、そして私は
ああ、トポロジーとスペクトル空間と
ああ、それはそのように見える
うん、私の合成を作ったと言えるだろう
快適な
あなたが言っていることはわかる、うんうん
クール、まあ、私は、他に何もないと思う
他には何もなくて、クルド人が入ってきている
so
what do you think i uh would be remiss
not to ask how you thought active
inference plays into this
or what you thought about active
inference yeah without the end
like that's what you're saying right how
the interfaces actually intersect
or just right what what comes to mind
when you think about active inference
and cybernetics and control theory
and where some of this like agent in the
niche goes from
there's the analytical there's the
philosophical and then
not getting into the the theology of
what's real but just like
there's the agents the model about how
the agent is operating in the niche
so where does what does active inference
make yeah well i guess
um from like uh you know the way that
you've defined it so again i'm
interested
into okay so here's like uh i guess my
my knowledge of it right
so here's an agent with uh i mean i
guess
right with a certain interface i quote
interact with you like whatever that
means
and so in my opinion the way that things
are interacting
is through how many morphisms they
actually generate so it's actually
categorical
so i don't do this sort of like
analytical thing like philosoph
philosophical because again i i'm from
this higher space so if you just
アクティブインファレンスを見てみると、たぶん
カテゴリー理論を通して
今、実際に何が起こっているのかというと、ああ
ああ、興味深い、何に対して
私の相互作用がどの瞬間に
このような反対のエージェントや何かに
私を反射的なサブカテゴリーに投げ込むのか
そこで私は実際にただ
自分自身と相互作用しているので、私は本当に
興味があります
インターフェース理論がどこで
実際に
トポロジカルローカリゼーションに出会うことができるのか、私は
話していたように
だから、私は思う、ええ、私が好きなことは
これが、あなたがやっていることのように聞こえることです
私がやっていることと同じことを、どのように
異なる言語で、だからトポロジカルな
ローカリゼーション、そう、私はどうやって
逆を見つけて、より関連付けるのかに興味があります
そして私のスペースを作る
強くなる、ええ、通過することで
これらの反射的サブカテゴリー
だからもしそれが、ああ、アクティブ
インファレンスがこれらのエージェントの
交換と実際に
相互作用しているのは非常に興味深い
私が受け取っているものがどのように
あなたの情報
私のデータ構造に取り込まれて、私は
知らない
その受信がどのように見えるのか
その端で、だから私はただ言いたい
カテゴリー的に、私たちがやっていることは
同じことのように聞こえる
そしてそれは私にとってかなりメタ的になる
私はちょっと
ええ、あなたの情報を取り込んで、それが
私のシステムの一部になり、それは私の
自分の反射的サブカテゴリーの一部で、私は好きだ
don't know
like keep moving on or something but you
know if it's about if
it's about how interfaces work um i
still don't know how you got the
original interface
so um i don't know if that means
anything
you know some of these ideas we talked a
little bit about
in active inference 17 2.0.1.2
because that was the paper that we
focused on for those weeks by
fields and glazebrook but i think what
you have pointed to today really
also gives us a lot of things to go over
again and think about
so maybe we can um stay in touch and
if you ever want to join for another
conversation or
他の方法で参加できればいいですね
素晴らしいです、なぜなら本当に考えさせられるからです
そして私は願っています
私たちのラボが楽しんでくれるといいですね、はい、とても楽しかったです、ありがとう
本当に楽しい時間を過ごしました
ありがとう、さようなら